<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Submit | SecDr]]></title>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/categories/submit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-02T10:09:59+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://secdr.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SecDr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SCI 投稿全过程信件模板一览]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/13/sci-tou-gao-quan-guo-cheng-xin-jian-mo-ban-%5B%3F%5D-lan/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-13T00:54:28+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/13/sci-tou-gao-quan-guo-cheng-xin-jian-mo-ban-[?]-lan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SCI 投稿全过程信件模板一览（出处不详，仅供参考）：</p>

<h3>一、最初投稿Cover letter</h3>

<p>Dear Editors:</p>

<p>We would like to submit the enclosed manuscript entitled “Paper Title”, which we wish to be considered for publication in “Journal Name”. No conflict of interest exits in the submission of this manuscript, and manuscript is approved by all authors for publication. I would like to declare on behalf of my co-authors that the work described was original research that has not been published previously, and not under consideration for publication elsewhere, in whole or in part. All the authors listed have approved the manuscript that is enclosed.</p>

<p>In this work, we evaluated …… (简要介绍一下论文的创新性). I hope this paper is suitable for “Journal Name”. The following is a list of possible reviewers for your consideration:</p>

<pre><code>1) Name A   E-mail: ××××@××××
2) Name B   E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<p>We deeply appreciate your consideration of our manuscript, and we look forward to receiving comments from the reviewers. If you have any queries, please don’t hesitate to contact me at the address below.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Thank you and best regards.</p>

<pre><code>Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author: 
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<h3>二、催稿信</h3>

<p>Dear Prof. ×××:</p>

<p>Sorry for disturbing you. I am not sure if it is the right time to contact you to inquire about the status of my submitted manuscript titled “Paper Title”. (ID: 文章稿号), although the status of “With Editor” has been lasting for more than two months, since submitted to journal three months ago. I am just wondering that my manuscript has been sent to reviewers or not?</p>

<p>I would be greatly appreciated if you could spend some of your time check the status for us. I am very pleased to hear from you on the reviewer’s comments.
Thank you very much for your consideration.</p>

<pre><code>Best regards! 
Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author: 
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<h3>三、修改稿Cover letter</h3>

<p>Dear Dr/ Prof..（写上负责你文章编辑的姓名，显得尊重，因为第一次的投稿不知道具体负责的编辑，只能用通用的Editors）:</p>

<p>On behalf of my co-authors, we thank you very much for giving us an opportunity to revise our manuscript, we appreciate editor and reviewers very much for their positive and constructive comments and suggestions on our manuscript entitled “Paper Title”. (ID: 文章稿号).</p>

<p>We have studied reviewer’s comments carefully and have made revision which marked in red in the paper. We have tried our best to revise our manuscript according to the comments. Attached please find the revised version, which we would like to submit for your kind consideration.</p>

<p>We would like to express our great appreciation to you and reviewers for comments on our paper. Looking forward to hearing from you.
Thank you and best regards.</p>

<pre><code>Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author:
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<h3>四、修改稿回答审稿人的意见（最重要的部分）</h3>

<p>List of Responses</p>

<p>Dear Editors and Reviewers:</p>

<p>Thank you for your letter and for the reviewers’ comments concerning our manuscript entitled “Paper Title” (ID: 文章稿号). Those comments are all valuable and very helpful for revising and improving our paper, as well as the important guiding significance to our researches. We have studied comments carefully and have made correction which we hope meet with approval. Revised portion are marked in red in the paper. The main corrections in the paper and the responds to the reviewer’s comments are as flowing:</p>

<p>Responds to the reviewer’s comments:</p>

<p>Reviewer #1:</p>

<pre><code>1. Response to comment: (……简要列出意见……)
</code></pre>

<p>Response: ××××××</p>

<pre><code>2. Response to comment: (……简要列出意见……)
</code></pre>

<p>Response: ××××××
    。。。。。。</p>

<p>逐条意见回答，切忌一定不能有遗漏</p>

<p>针对不同的问题有下列几个礼貌术语可适当用用：</p>

<ul>
<li>We are very sorry for our negligence of ……&hellip;</li>
<li>We are very sorry for our incorrect writing ……&hellip;</li>
<li>It is really true as Reviewer suggested that……</li>
<li>We have made correction according to the Reviewer’s comments.</li>
<li>We have re-written this part according to the Reviewer’s suggestion</li>
<li>As Reviewer suggested that……</li>
<li>Considering the Reviewer’s suggestion, we have ……</li>
</ul>


<p>最后特意感谢一下这个审稿人的意见：</p>

<p>Special thanks to you for your good comments.</p>

<p>Reviewer #2:</p>

<p>同上述</p>

<p>Reviewer #3:</p>

<pre><code>××××××
</code></pre>

<p>Other changes:</p>

<ol>
<li>Line 60-61, the statements of “……” were corrected as “…………”</li>
<li>Line 107, “……” was added</li>
<li><p>Line 129, “……” was deleted
 ××××××</p>

<p> We tried our best to improve the manuscript and made some changes in the manuscript.  These changes will not influence the content and framework of the paper. And here we did not list the changes but marked in red in revised paper.
We appreciate for Editors/Reviewers’ warm work earnestly, and hope that the correction will meet with approval.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Once again, thank you very much for your comments and suggestions.</p>

<h3>五、文章接受后可以考虑感谢一下负责你文章的编辑或主编（根据需要）</h3>

<p>Dear Prof. ××××××:</p>

<p>Thanks very much for your kind work and consideration on publication of our paper. On behalf of my co-authors, we would like to express our great appreciation to editor and reviewers.
Thank you and best regards.</p>

<pre><code>Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author:
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<h3>六、询问校稿信件（如果文章接受后时间较长）</h3>

<p>Dear ×××:</p>

<p>Sorry for disturbing you. I am not sure if it is the right time to contact you to inquire about the status of our accepted manuscript titled “Paper Title” (ID: 文章稿号), since the copyright agreement for publication has been sent to you two months ago. I am just wondering that how long I can receive the proof of our manuscript from you?
I would be greatly appreciated if you could spend some of your time for a reply. I am very pleased to hear from you.</p>

<p>Thank you very much for your consideration.</p>

<pre><code>Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author:
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>

<h3>七、文章校稿信件</h3>

<p>Dear Mr. ×××:</p>

<p>Thanks very much for your kind letter about the proof of our paper titled “Paper Title” (ID: 文章稿号) for publication in “Journal Name”. We have finished the proof reading and checking carefully, and some corrections about the proof and the answers to the queries are provided below.</p>

<p>Corrections:</p>

<ol>
<li>In <strong><strong><strong> should be </strong></strong> (Page </strong><em>, Right column, line</em>**)</li>
<li>In <strong><strong> the “</strong></strong><em>” should be “</em><em><strong>” (Page </strong><strong>, Right column, line</strong></em>*)
Answers for “author queries”:</li>
<li>*********************.</li>
<li><hr /></li>
<li><hr /></li>
</ol>


<p>We greatly appreciate the efficient, professional and rapid processing of our paper by your team. If there is anything else we should do, please do not hesitate to let us know.</p>

<p>Thank you and best regards.</p>

<pre><code>Yours sincerely,
××××××
Corresponding author:
Name: ×××
E-mail: ××××@××××
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elsevier期刊投稿状态]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/12/elsevierqi-kan-tou-gao-zhuang-tai/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-12T16:58:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/12/elsevierqi-kan-tou-gao-zhuang-tai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>1 关于Elsevier旗下期刊投稿概述</h3>

<p>(1) Elsevier旗下共有1300多种期刊。投稿时采用的是Elsevier Editorial System (EES)投稿系统</p>

<p>(2) 审稿时间。通常不会超过半年，如果半年时间到，部分审稿意见没有返回，期刊社同样会把已返回的意见返回给你。</p>

<p>(3) 版权问题。一般会通过给你发几个PDF合同，然后你打印出来，用手填写，然后邮寄或者扫描后通过email发给他们。</p>

<p>(4) 投稿模板。通常很多人都会关心这个问题，这是投稿的第一步。但是Elsevier旗下期刊对投稿的模板没什么要求，只要
你比较注意排版，看着舒服就好。至于排版，录用后他们编辑会排版，然后让你来校正。建议，投稿时候不要考虑纸张页数，国外期刊不太关心期刊页数，只要按他们最后的排版不超过30页（好像是30页）一般不会收钱。</p>

<p>(5) 如果投稿论文分成几个部分，在投稿的时候就要分开，按照单独的论文投稿。不过要在Letter to Editor中要说明这是同一个论文。</p>

<p>(6) Elsevier旗下期刊投稿不收取审稿费，发表也不收取版面费，但超过一定页数会适当收取费用，如果用彩色印刷，也会收钱，他们不收则以，一收就比较多。</p>

<p>(7) 投稿时是否需要把图片和论文主题分开。这个本来不需要说的，网站上的要求就是如此，需要单独分开上传，但是以我的经验，如果论文图太多，特别是对于国内的网速慢，上传很不方便，可以直接把图放在论文中间，审稿阶段不用考虑图文分开，等录用后再图文分开。</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>2 Elsevier投稿状态总结</h3>

<p>(1) Submitted to Journal</p>

<p>刚提交的状态</p>

<p>(2) Manuscript received by Editorial Office</p>

<p>就是你的文章到了编辑手里了，证明投稿成功</p>

<p>(3) With editor　</p>

<p>如果在投稿的时候没有要求选择编辑，就先到主编那，主编会分派给别的编辑。这当中就会有另两个状态：</p>

<pre><code>1) Awaiting Editor Assignment指派责任编辑 
Editor assigned是把你的文章分给一个编辑处理了。
2) Editor Declined Invitation 也可能编辑会拒绝邀请，这就需要重新指定编辑
3) technical check in progress 检查你的文章符不符合期刊投稿要求
</code></pre>

<p>(4) 编辑接手处理后也会有2种状态
    1) Decision Letter Being Prepared 就是编辑没找审稿人就自己决定了，
    2) Reviewer(s) invited 找到审稿人了，就开始审稿</p>

<p>(5) Under review</p>

<p>这应该是一个漫长的等待。当然前面各步骤也可能很慢的，要看编辑的处理情况。如果被邀请审稿人不想审，就会decline，编辑会重新邀请别的审稿人。</p>

<p>(6) Required Reviews Completed</p>

<p>审稿人的意见已上传，审稿结束，等待编辑决定</p>

<p>(7) Evaluating Recommendation</p>

<p>评估审稿人的意见，随后你将收到编辑给你的decision</p>

<p>(8) Minor revision/Major revision</p>

<p>这个时候可以稍微庆祝一下了，问题不大了，因为有修改就有可能。</p>

<p>(9) Revision Submitted to Journal.</p>

<p>又开始了一个循环。</p>

<p>(10) Accepted 文章被接受</p>

<p>如果不要再审，只是小修改，编辑看后会马上显示这个状态，但如果要再审也会有上面的部分状态。一步会比较快，但也有慢的。看杂志的。还有个状态是Rejected。希望不要出现。</p>

<p>(11) Transfer copyright form 签版权协议</p>

<p>(12) uncorrected proof 等待你校对样稿</p>

<p>(13) In Press, Corrected Proof 文章在印刷中，且该清样已经过作者校对</p>

<p>(14) Manuscript Sent to Production 排版</p>

<p>(15) in production 出版中</p>

<p>备注：</p>

<p>　　现在Elsevier的绝大多数期刊，增加了Technical Checking这一关，由专门的Editorial office来审查论文的语言、格式、排版、图片等等，也就是说，审查你的投稿是否符合Guide for Authors中的各项要求。</p>

<p>论文投稿之后，状态是Submitted to Journal，后成为with editor。注意：这里的Editor实际上不是期刊的主编，而是Editorial office里负责论文格式、排版、语言审查的编辑。如果论文通过了技术性审查，状态重新变为Submitted to Journal，表明论文通过了第一关。之后，如果不出意外，论文状态将会再次变成With Editor，这里的Editor才是真正的期刊主编。到了这一步，你的论文才会进入under review状态。需要说明的是，如果你的论文没通过Technical Checking这一关，你的论文就会退回，要求做格式、语言上的修改，然后鼓励你再投。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[论文返修模板3]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/12/lun-wen-fan-xiu-mo-ban-3/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-12T06:39:29+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/12/12/lun-wen-fan-xiu-mo-ban-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>博客中已近有一些论文返修的套话，这里再补充一些模板，方便大家返修的时候使用：</p>

<p>Dear Editor，</p>

<p>We would like to thank the editor for giving us a chance to resubmit the paper, and also thank the reviewers for giving us constructive suggestions which would help us both in English and in depth to improve the quality of the paper. Here we submit a new version of our manuscript with the title “………………………”, which has been modified according to the reviewers’ suggestions. Efforts were also made to correct the mistakes and improve the English of the manuscript. We mark all the changes in red in the revised manuscript.</p>

<p>Sincerely yours,</p>

<p>XXX</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The following is a point-to-point response to the two reviewers’ comments.</p>

<h3>Reviewer #1:</h3>

<p>General comments:</p>

<p>Reviewer #1: The paper presents an interesting experimental investigation to assess the photocatalytic degradation of polyethylene plastic with goethite under UV irradiation. The research work is clearly presented but the conclusions, the introduction and other parts of the paper relate the results obtained with unjustified claims about the impact of the work. In addition, the background information provided in the introduction part needs significant enrichment. In particular:</p>

<p>Answer: Thank you for the comments on the paper. We have revised the manuscript as suggested since we consider that some sentences or descriptions in the Conclusion part are not so accurate based on the results.  Page 3, line 46: recycling is not available…</p>

<p>Even though a large amount of agricultural plastic waste in burnt or buried in the fields, some quantities of specific categories of good quality agricultural plastic waste are recycled in several countries while research efforts and projects are in progress to improve the corresponding percentage. The authors should refer to the corresponding recent literature.</p>

<p>Answer:Yes. Your opinions inspired us and we revised the manuscript accordingly. In the revised paper, the sentence “Recycling is not available for economy,” was changed to “In order to reduce costs, the thickness of application agriculture films in some regions in China is less than 0.005 mm result in diffcult to recycle, And because the process of recycling is expensive and time-consuming, only a small percentage of the agricultural plastic waste is currently recycled at the end of cultivation in China ”(Page 3 line 49-52).
Page 3, line 76: biodegradable and photodegradable….</p>

<p>There are developments in the area of biodegradable materials that indicate the opposite. Concerning photodegradable materials, they are not considered to represent a solution as they have not been proven to be biodegradable. The authors should refer to the corresponding recent literature.</p>

<p>Answer: Thank you for reminding us the improper description on the study. We have the improper parts revised accordingly and hope that this new manuscript will be convincing ( Page 3 line 52-55).
Page 4, line 65: find an eco-friendly….</p>

<p>The best eco-friendly disposal for agricultural plastic waste is recycling and for non-recyclable materials, energy recovery. Degrading materials produced from fossil sources is not an eco-friendly disposal! The authors should refer to the corresponding recent literature.</p>

<p>Answer: Thank the reviewer for the comments. We’ve recognized that some of the descriptions in the previous copy were really not so accurate and a little bit arbitrary due to our poor English level and the study on recent literature. After consulting more references, we therefore revised paper to be more reasonable and convincing.
Page 4, line 66: to carbon dioxide and water….</p>

<p>Conversion of fossil oil based materials into carbon dioxide and water is much worse than converting renewable-based materials into carbon dioxide and water</p>

<p>Answer: Thank the reviewer for the comments. We’ve recognized that this description in the previous copy were not accurate, due to our poor study on recent literature. The sentence “it is very important to find an eco-friendly disposal of plastic waste where they degrade to carbon dioxide and water under the sunlight irradiation without producing toxic byproducts.” has been deleted.
Page 6, line 112: volatile products….</p>

<p>Define the products.</p>

<p>Answer: We have defined the volatile products in Page 6 line 124-125.
Page 9, line 185: eco-friendly disposal….</p>

<p>The claims of the authors that this technique is an eco-friendly one are not justified. The conclusions and other parts of the paper need to be rewritten and limit the scope of the presented research work to the technical objectives without deriving unjustified general conclusions and claims about the impact of this work.</p>

<p>Answer: Thank the reviewer for the comments. We’ve recognized that this description in the previous copy were not accurate. The sentence “The development of this kind of composite polymer can lead to an eco-friendly disposal of polymer wastes.” was changed to “The present paper intends to study goethite as photocatalytst for degradating plastic. Further attention could be focused on the application of the technique.” (Page 9 line 192-194).</p>

<h3>Reviewer #2:</h3>

<p>/1. Title and abstract should indicate that the work has been done with PE-Goethite composite film.</p>

<p>Answer: Your suggestion is greatly appreciated. We agree and therefore change the title to: Solid-phase photocatalytic degradation of polyethylene–goethite composite film under UV-light irradiation.</p>

<p>/2. Please revise the first paragraph of &lsquo;Introduction&rsquo;.  It is difficult to understand.  In general, the language of the paper should be revisited.</p>

<p>Answer: The Introduction part has been rewritten both in contents and in English. We particularly revised some sentences since they are not correct or so confusing.</p>

<p>/3. Materials and methods - Details of the chemicals to be furnished</p>

<p>Answer: The reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the details of the chemicals has been shown in Page 4 line 79-83.</p>

<p>/4. Characterization are required for PE (Molecular weight, grade) and Goethite prepared (particle size, BET surface area, SEM-EDS and XRD)</p>

<p>Answer: The reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the characterization for PE has been shown in Page 4 line 79. The Goethite prepared (particle size, BET surface area, SEM and XRD) has been reported by Liao et al. (2007), We clarify that in the revised manuscript in Page 5 line 91-93.</p>

<p>/5. A schematic diagram of the experimental set up to be given</p>

<p>Answer: The reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and a schematic diagram of the experimental has been given in Fig. 1 in the present paper. The original Fig. 1. was changed to Fig. 2 and Fig. 3.</p>

<p>/6. Results - A rate equation should be proposed from the time-weight data</p>

<p>Answer: The reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the rate equation a schematic diagram of the experimental has been given in Table. 1in the present paper.</p>

<p>/7. A few data are required to show the influence of process parameters such as goethite loading, intensity of UV radiation.</p>

<p>Answer: Reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the influence of goethite loading has been shown in Fig. 2 in the present paper. And the influence of intensity of UV radiation has been shown in Fig. 3 in the present paper. The original Fig. 2 was changed to Fig. 4 and The original Fig. 3 was changed to Fig. 5 in the present paper.</p>

<p>/8. Until other intermediates are isolated, upto Eqn.(7) (line 162) is sufficient.</p>

<p>Answer: Reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and We changed the Eqns as recommended. Eqs. (8)-(12) are deleted and Eqn.(7) was change to “–(CH2CH2)– + .OH → degradationproducts” (Page 9 line 184).</p>

<p>/9. Figure 3 and 4: 3 pairs are required, namely (i) Only PE film before and after irradiation, (ii) PE-Goethite film (0.4wt %) - before and after irradiation (iii) PE-Goethite film (1.0 wt %) - before and after irradiation.</p>

<p>Answer: Reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the original Fig. 3 and 4 was changed to Fig .5 in the present paper.</p>

<p>/10. Point 3 above is also applicable for SEM photographs. Please rearrange and clearly mark the difference between the films before and after irradiation for both SEM and FTIR results.</p>

<p>Answer: Thank the reviewer and editor’s for the comments. During the revision of the paper, we did a supplementary experiment got some new SEM photographs, which has been shown in Fig. 4 in the present paper. And The FTIR results has been rearranged in Fig.5 in the present paper, respectively.</p>

<p>/11. It should be clearly mentioned in the conclusion that the degradation was more when goethite loading and intensity of light both were more</p>

<p>Answer: The reviewer and editor’s suggestions have been adopted and the conclusions has been changed in Page 9 line 192-198.</p>

<p>原文出处: <a href="http://emuch.net/html/201004/1977263.html">wzz525-文章要求修改，求response to review的模板</a>;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[论文返修一些很有用的套话II]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/10/03/response-letters/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-03T13:14:29+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/10/03/response-letters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>总结了一部分万能的套话，以体现我们对杂志社编辑和审稿人的尊重。</p>

<p>1、Firstly, we would like to thank you for your kind letter and for reviewers’ constructive comments concerning our article (Manuscript No.:XXXXX).These comments are all valuable and helpful for improving our article. All the authors have seriously discussed about all these comments. According to the reviewers’comments, we have tried best to modify our manuscript to meet with the requirements of your journal. In this revised version, changes to our manuscript within the document were all highlighted by using red colored text.Point-by-point responses to the reviewers are listed below this letter.</p>

<p>2、If there are any other modifications we could make, we would like very much to modify them and we really appreciate your help. Thank you very much for your help.</p>

<p>3、Thanks. We have corrected these mistakes based on your suggestions.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>4、Thank you again for your positive comments and valuable suggestions toimprove the quality of our manuscript.</p>

<p>5、we were really sorry for your careless mistakes. Thank you for your reminding.</p>

<p>6、Thanks for your nice suggestions. We have formatted all the references.</p>

<p>7、It is with excitement that I resubmit to you a revised version of manuscript （稿号） for the 杂志名. Thank you for giving me the opportunity to revise and resubmit this manuscript. In keeping with my last communication with you, I am resubmitting this revision before the agreed upondeadline. I appreciate the time and detail provided by each reviewer and by you and have incorporated the suggested changes into the manuscript to the best of my ability. The manuscript has certainly benefited from these insightful revision suggestions. I look forward to working with you and the reviewers to move this manuscript closer to publication in the杂志名. （返修有拖延时用）</p>

<p>8、I have responded specifically to each suggestion below, beginning with your own. To make the changes easier to identify where necessary, I have numbered them.</p>

<p>9、Thank you again for your positive comments on our manuscript. 杂志名 is an influential journal which aims to improve ourunderstanding of cancer prevention/other. From all the papers published in your journal, readers have been learning a lot. Hopefully, we could have our article been considered of publication in your journal. Should there been any other corrections we could make, please feel free to contact us.</p>

<p>10、Thank you for your kind comments on ourmanuscript entitled “文章名”. We have carefully revised the manuscript according to the reviewer’s comments. Based on the suggestions, we have made an extensive modification on the revised manuscript. Detailed revision was shown as follows. The changes to our manuscript within the document were aslo highlighted by using red colored text.</p>

<p>11、We feel great thanks for your professional review work onour article. As you are concerned, there are several problems that need to beaddressed. According to your nice suggestions, we have made extensivecorrections to our previous draft, the detailed corrections are listed below.</p>

<p>12、According to the reviewer’s comments, we have revised the manuscript extensively. If there are any other modifications we could make, we would like very much to modify them and we really appreciate your help. We hope that our manuscript could be considered for publication in your journal. Thank you very much for your help.</p>

<p>13、On behalf of all the contributing authors, I would like to express our sincere appreciations of your letter and reviewers’ constructive comments concerning our article entitled “XXX文章” (Manuscript No.:XXXX). These comments are all valuable and helpful for improving our article. According to the associate editor and reviewers’ comments,we have made extensive modifications to our manuscript and supplemented extra data to make our results convincing. In this revised version, changes to ourmanuscript were all highlighted within the document by using red colored text. Point-by-pointresponses to the nice associate editor and two nice reviewers are listed below this letter.</p>

<p>14、We would like to thank you first for all the positive comments of ourmanuscript (No.: XXXX) entitled “XXXXX”. We really appreciate your help and patience. We also think highly of the comment sof both reviewers who kindly provide professional suggestions on our manuscript.we have seriously thought about them and provided our response to reviewers. Forthe detailed response, please see below.</p>

<p><a href="http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzA3ODU1NjUyNw==&amp;mid=212599913&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=bfe1661e02ad61c8166724f2845e337c&amp;scene=23&amp;srcid=0930Ad9myRyQ2IGB9frfHWGh#rd">原文地址: 实验万事屋-论文返修（response letter)一些很有用的套话II</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cover Letter详解及相关模板]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/06/02/cover-letterxiang-jie-ji-xiang-guan-mo-ban/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-02T14:52:53+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/06/02/cover-letterxiang-jie-ji-xiang-guan-mo-ban</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>1、 什么是cover letter？</p>

<p>指的是投稿信</p>

<p>2、cover letter的内容主要包括那些？</p>

<p>应该简述所投稿件的核心内容、主要发现和意义，拟投期刊，对稿件处理有无特殊要求等（如“not to review” list）。另外，请附上主要作者的中文姓名、通讯地址、电话、传真和e-mail地址。此外有的杂志要求推荐几位审稿人及其联系方式。以及谁已经阅读过该文（当然是牛人）。
我投的那个杂志是要求说明你论文研究的意义，以及与这个杂志的相关性，另外还有的可能要写明你没有一搞多投等。此外临床实验要求写明符合伦理学要求。</p>

<p>3、 如何写cover letter？</p>

<p>各个杂志的具体要求是不一样的，在杂志的guide for authors一般会有要求。如果没有具体的要求，大家可按照通用要求处理。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>4、常用模板：</p>

<p>（1）Cover letter</p>

<pre><code>Dear Mr. **

1/. The work described has not been submitted elsewhere for publication, in whole or in part, and all the authors listed have approved the manuscript that is enclosed.

2/. I have read and have abided by the statement of ethical standards for manuscripts submitted to Neuroscience.

kind regards.
Your sincerely,
通讯作者
</code></pre>

<p>（2）</p>

<pre><code>Dear Dr. 主编name:
We submit our manuscript entitled " 文章title" to 杂志名for publication.
接着简单介绍你文章的主要创新点和意义，不易过多，但要突出新意和关键点。
All authors have seen the manuscript and approved to submit to your journal. 
Thank you very much for your attention and consideration. 

Sincerely yours, 
通讯作者
</code></pre>

<p>（3）</p>

<pre><code>Dear Dr. 主编name:
We submit our manuscript entitled " 文章title" to 杂志名for publication.
接着简单介绍你文章的主要创新点和意义，不易过多，但要突出新意和关键点。
All authors have seen the manuscript and approved to submit to your journal. 
Thank you very much for your attention and consideration. 

Sincerely yours, 
通讯作者
</code></pre>

<p>（4）</p>

<pre><code>Dr. ***
Editor-in-Chief, ***
(add address) January 22, 2003 

Dear Dr. **,

Enclosed herewith please find 3 copies of a MS by: ‘***. *** and ***’ entitled: “**********”, which we would like to submit for publication in the ‘******'.

Looking forward to your decision,
With kind personal regards,
Sincerely yours,

*****
Professor of ***
</code></pre>

<p>（5）</p>

<pre><code>Dear Prof. Gil:
This is a manuscript by**and **entitled “.......”. It is submitted to be considered for publication as a “...” in your journal. This paper is new. Neither the entire paper nor any part of its content has been published or has been accepted elsewhere. It is not being submitted to any other journal.
We believe the paper may be of particular interest to the readers of your journal as it ........
Correspondence should be addressed to **at the following address, phone and fax number, and email address:
...
Thanks very much for your attention to our paper. 
Sincerely yours,
**
</code></pre>

<p>5、 例文：下面例文都来自丁香园战友，在此一并感谢。</p>

<p>（一）</p>

<pre><code>Date: Sep 15, 2003
Dear Editors:

On behalf of my co-authors, I am submitting the enclosed material “ TITLE ” for possible publication in JOURNAL. 

We certify that we have participated sufficiently in the work to take public responsibility for the appropriateness of the experimental design and method, and the collection, analysis, and interpretation of the data.

We have reviewed the final version of the manuscript and approve it for publication. To the best of our knowledge and belief, this manuscript has not been published in whole or in part nor is it being considered for publication elsewhere.

Best Regards.

Yours Sincerely,

NAME,ADRESS,EMAIL,FAX
</code></pre>

<p>（二）</p>

<pre><code>Dear Dr Regino Perez-Polo：
Enclosed are a manuscript by su jian, yang kun, chen zhihua．Su jian titled“Hypothermia after Acute Ischemic Stroke
”．It is submitted to be considered for publication as a“review" in your journal．This paper is～•Neither the entire paper nor any part of its content has been published or has been accepted elsewhere ．It is not being submitted to any other journal．
We believe the paper may be of particular interest to the readers of your journal.
Correspondence and phone calls about the paper should be directed to Su jian at the following address，phone and fax number，and e-mail address：

Su jian
Institute:, 
Adress:
Tel：
Fax:
E-mail：
Thanks very much for your attention to our paper．
Sincerely yours，
Su jian
</code></pre>

<p>（三）</p>

<pre><code>Dear Editor,

We would like to submit the enclosed manuscript entitled "GDNF Acutely Modulates Neuronal Excitability and A-type Potassium Channels in Midbrain Dopaminergic Neurons", which we wish to be considered for publication in Nature Neuroscience. 

GDNF has long been thought to be a potent neurotrophic factor for the survival of midbrain dopaminergic neurons, which are degenerated in Parkinson’s disease. In this paper, we report an unexpected, acute effect of GDNF on A-type potassium channels, leading to a potentiation of neuronal excitability, in the dopaminergic neurons in culture as well as in adult brain slices. Further, we show that GDNF regulates the K+ channels through a mechanism that involves activation of MAP kinase. Thus, this study has revealed, for the first time, an acute modulation of ion channels by GDNF. Our findings challenge the classic view of GDNF as a long-term survival factor for midbrain dopaminergic neurons, and suggest that the normal function of GDNF is to regulate neuronal excitability, and consequently dopamine release. These results may also have implications in the treatment of Parkinson’s disease. 

Due to a direct competition and conflict of interest, we request that Drs. XXX of Harvard Univ., and YY of Yale Univ. not be considered as reviewers. With thanks for your consideration, I am 

Sincerely yours,
</code></pre>

<p>（四）</p>

<pre><code>Dear **.
We would like to submit the enclosed manuscript entitled " *** ", which we wish to be considered for publication in **journal. 
We believe that two aspects of this manuscript will make it interesting to general readers of **journal. First, ***. Second, ***. Further, ***.
Thank you very much your considering our manuscript for potential publication. I'm looking forward to hearing from you soon.

Best wishes.
</code></pre>

<p>（五）</p>

<pre><code>To: SOLA Chief Editor
Division of Geoenvironmental Sciences
University of Tsukuba
Tsukuba 305-8572, JAPAN
E-Mail: sola@sakura.cc.tsukuba.ac.jp
Dear Sirs,
I am sending herewith a copy of the manuscript, which I would like to submit to SOLA, the Electronic Journal of the Meteorological Society of Japan.
The paper is entitled:
Energy Spectrum Proportional to the Squared Phase Speed of
Rossby Modes in the General Circulation of the Atmosphere
by H. L. Tanaka, Yasushi Watarai, and Takahiro Kanda.
Copy of the Abstract:
In this study, energy spectrum of the large-scale atmospheric motions is examined in the framework of the 3D normal mode decomposition. The horizontal scale of disturbance is measured by the phase speed of a Rossby mode c. According to the analysis result for the barotropic component of the atmosphere, we obtain a characteristic energy spectrum with distinct slopes for the turbulence and wave regimes separated by the spherical Rhines speed. In order to explain the observational finding that the energy spectrum is proportional to c^2, we put forward a hypothesis based on the criterion of Rossby wave breaking such that the local meridional gradient of potential vorticity becomes negative, dq/dy &lt; 0, somewhere in the domain. With a constant m describing a total mass of the atmosphere for unit area, we have shown that the barotropic energy spectrum of the general circulation E can be represented as E=mc^2.
Corresponding Author:
Dr. Hiroshi L. Tanaka
Division of Geoenvironmental Sciences
University of Tsukuba
Tsukuba 305-8572, JAPAN
Tel: +81-29-853-4502
Fax: +81-29-853-6879
E-Mail: tanaka@sakura.cc.tsukuba.ac.jp
I hereby certify that this paper consists of original, unpublished work which is not under consideration for publication elsewhere.
Desired Editors in Charge:
Kimoto, Masahide University of Tokyo
Mak, Mankin University of Illinois
Five Potential Reviewers:
Name-1, e-mail address-1
Name-2, e-mail address-2
Name-3, e-mail address-3
Name-4, e-mail address-4
Name-5, e-mail address-5
The original manuscript and figures will be transferred, following the instruction by the Editorial Committee when the paper is accepted. I hope your favorable consideration for publication to SOLA.
Sincerely,
Hiroshi L. Tanaka
Attachment: PDF file of the manuscript.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
