<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Write | SecDr]]></title>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/categories/write/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-01T23:19:30-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://secdr.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SecDr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[论文返修有用的开场白]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/06/01/response-letter-sentence/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-01T23:16:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/06/01/response-letter-sentence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>又总结了一部分万能的开场白，足以体现我们对杂志社编辑和审稿人的尊重。</p>

<p>1、It is with excitement that I resubmit to you a revised version of manuscript “文章题目” for the &ldquo;杂志名&rdquo;. Thank you for giving me the opportunity to revise and resubmit this manuscript. In keeping with my last communication with you, I am resubmitting this revision before the agreed upon deadline, March 16, 2012. I appreciate the time and detail provided by each reviewer and by you and have incorporated the suggested changes into the manuscript to the best of my ability. The manuscript has certainly benefited from these insightful revision suggestions. I look forward to working with you and the reviewers to move this manuscript closer to publication in the 杂志名. （这段拍马屁的写得真长哇，憋不出来的可以参考下）</p>

<p>2、I have responded specifically to each suggestion below, beginning with your own. To make the changes easier to identify where necessary, I have numbered them.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>3、I am pleased to resubmit for publication the revised version of 文章在杂志社的编号 “文章题目”. I appreciated the constructive criticisms of the Associate Editor and the reviewers. I have addressed each of their concerns as outlined below. （这样的开场白简单点）</p>

<p>4、Sincerest thanks for your response and reviewers comments on our manuscript. We sincerely apologise for the great time it has taken us to respond to these comments (due to force majeaure with first author), and hope that a revised version of the manuscript will still be considered by 杂志名. We have modified the paper in response to the extensive and insightful reviewer comments. We have added additional explanations for non-haematologists and additional table (Table 1) to fully address the reviewer’s comments. Furthermore we have rewritten sections of the manuscript and we hope that this comply with the referee’s remarks. We will respond to the comments point counter point. （这段挺长的，还就返修时间过长进行了致歉）</p>

<p>5、Thank you for reading our manuscript and reviewing it, which will help us improve it to a better scientific level. We revised our manuscript, and quite a lot of changes have taken place. So we have sent the revised manuscript, and a version containing all the changes to be visible.</p>

<p>At the following, the points mentioned by the reviewers will be discussed: (其实我比较喜欢这种简单直白的开场）</p>

<p>6、The authors would like to thank the reviewers for their time and their valuable comments. Before addressing each of the comments below, we would like to make a general remark regarding the intent of the manuscript and the choice of the journal.</p>

<p>We chose &ldquo;XX杂志社&rdquo; because it is an applied journal publishing papers that will help clinical medical physicists perform their responsibilities more effectively and efficiently, and for the increased benefit of the patient. We feel that this journal is appropriate for our manuscript that we intend to be a practical paper which is helpful for a hospital physicist.</p>

<p>We deliberately went into more details in parts of the introduction and the methods section explaining specifics of CBCT, since the target audience might not be interested in the more fundamental papers in other journals covering the topic. We obviously need to quote all sources correctly and will do so at the places where we had missed before. （让我亮瞎眼的拍马屁，想抄的尽管抄）</p>

<p>7、Please find enclosed the response to the comments of reviewers. The manuscript has been carefully revised in response to the reviewers’comments and suggestions; detailed responses to their comments are below. Our reply is in italic font, whereas the reviewers’ specific comments are not italicized. We thank the reviewers for their suggestions, which have significantly improved this m/s.</p>

<p>总结了一部分万能的套话，足以体现我们对杂志社编辑和审稿人的尊重。
1、According to the associate editor and reviewers’ comments, we have made extensive modifications to our manuscript and supplemented extra data to make our results convincing.
2、In this revised version, changes to our manuscript were all highlighted within the document by using red colored text.
3、Thank you for your nice comments on our article. According to your suggestions, we have supplemented several data here and corrected several mistakes in our previous draft. Based on your comments, we also attached a point-by-point letter to you and the other two reviewers. We have made extensive revisions to our previous draft. The detailed point-by-point responses are listed below.
4、Thanks for your help. We feel really sorry for our carelessness.
5、Thank you for your reminding. You and the other two reviewers’ comments are all of great importance to our article. All of these comments have contributed a lot to improve the quality of our article. After this revision, we have written a point-by-point response letter to you as you can see above. Meanwhile, we also wrote a point-by-point response letter to the other two nice reviewers to acknowledge their helps and denote where we made revisions.
6、We feel great thanks for your professional review work on our article. As you are concerned, there are several problems that need to be addressed. According to your nice suggestions, we have made extensive corrections to our previous draft. We have added necessary data to supplement our results and edited our article extensively. The detailed corrections are listed below.
7、We feel sorry that we did not provide enough information about XXXX.
8、it is really a giant mistake to the whole quality of our article. We feel sorry for our carelessness. We have corrected it and we also feel great thanks for your point out.
9、thanks for your suggestions. We feel sorry for our poor writings, however, we do invite a friend of us who is a native English speaker from USA help polish our article. Due to our friend’s help, the article was edited extensively. And we hope the revised manuscript could be acceptable for you.
10、thanks for your careful checks. We are sorry for our carelessness. Based on your comments, we have made the corrections to make the unit harmonized within the whole manuscript.
11、your suggestion really means a lot to us. Yes, it would be more understandable if we XXX.
12、According to your suggestion, we have corrected the “XXX” into “XXX”.
13、 thanks for your correction. It was indeed a serious grammatical error. And we have corrected it according to your suggestion.
14、thanks for your suggestions. We feel sorry for the improper wording. We have used “XXXX” as you suggested.
15、According to the reviewer’s comments, we have revised the manuscript extensively. If there are any other modifications we could make, we would like very much to modify them and we really appreciate your help. “xxxx” is a journal of great popularity and prestige. We hope that our manuscript could be considered for publication in your journal. Thank you very much for your help.</p>

<p>原文地址：<a href="http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzA3ODU1NjUyNw==&amp;mid=208866198&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=d363bd37e629dbdbe01de3a14a9710ae&amp;scene=5#rd">论文返修（response letter）最尼玛有用的开场白</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[论文返修那些事儿]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/21/paper-response-thing/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-21T16:43:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/21/paper-response-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>审稿人也是人，不要无故地增加他们的痛苦，今天来讲一讲写response letter有哪些注意事项。</p>

<h3>Do&rsquo;s</h3>

<ol>
<li>与从事相关领域的朋友、导师或师兄师姐讨论，听取他们的意见（在医院的小伙伴就不用试这一条了，多半不是没人理就是白讨论，个人意见，勿拍);</li>
<li>完整地地回复审稿人的意见，不要遗漏任何问题；</li>
<li>如果你不同意审稿人的意见，请保持礼貌；</li>
<li>如果需要，可以引用参考文献或未发表的数据来支持自己的观点；</li>
<li>不要拖沓，收到返修后要尽快写回复，并且把改过的地方标识出来。</li>
</ol>


<h3>Don’ts</h3>

<ol>
<li>不要跟审稿人争论每一个问题，在一些无关紧要的小细节上，在并不影响文章价值的前提下，让一让审稿人；</li>
<li>不要把审稿人的批评当做是个人攻击；</li>
<li>如果审稿人要看原始数据，不要拒绝；</li>
<li>不要使用“we completely disagree”、“the referee obviously does not know this field”这样的话，会伤了审稿人的心。</li>
</ol>


<!--more-->


<p>可以使用委婉在回复，如下：</p>

<pre><code>We agree with the referee that……,but
The referee is right to point out….,yet
In accordance with the referees’wishes,we have now changed this sentence to…
Whilst we agree with the referee that……..
It is true that…,but
We acknowledge that our paper might have been…., but
We too were disappointed by the low response rate…
We agree that this is an important area that requires furthr research…..
We support the referee's assertion that….,although
With all due respect to the reviewer,we felt that this point is  not correct…
</code></pre>

<h3>文章几种状态的应对方法：</h3>

<p>Accept with minor revision</p>

<p>如果你很幸运，只要小修，这种情况下，不要argue太多，速度改了回复给杂志社，在主编还对你的文章有所印象时，速度返修往往也是速度接收。</p>

<p>Major revisions needed</p>

<p>这种情况下，有三条黄金原则：礼貌、完整、证据。不要低估大修的工作量，可以需要好几天铺在此事上。如果是大修，看上去没有什么接收的希望，也不要放弃，有些作者就这样放弃然后一字不改地投到别的杂志去，同领域的专家就那么几个，搞不好你的文章又送给同一个审稿人，华丽丽地忽视了他的意见，他会很不高兴的。即使改投杂志，也要根据上一本杂志的返修意见好好修改完文章后再投。</p>

<p>Journal requests a complete rewrite</p>

<p>这种情况下，你要好好思量下重新写文章是否值得。如果审稿人和主编告诉了你要如何改这篇文章，表示杂志社还是想要你的文章的，如果你照办了，拒绝你是要下多大狠心。但是如果审稿人只是冷冰冰的让你重写文章，没有给具体的建设性的意见，最好改投杂志，也许投入和产出不成正比。</p>

<p>Unsure if reject or possible resubmission?</p>

<p>比如这样的审稿意见“ we cannot accept your paper in its current form, but if you do decide to resubmit, then we would only consider a substantial revision”好像是个拒绝的言辞，但是又不确定，又好像是再给一次机会。这种情况下最好写邮件给杂志社，问问他们到底是如何想的，然后再决定，自个人揣测杂志社的意思不如写封邮件。</p>

<p>The outright rejection</p>

<p>如果你确实很想在这本杂志发文章，那么可以写信给杂志社，要求换责任主编再审，前提是你有足够的自信，当然希望是很渺茫的，好吧，希望是非常渺茫的。另一种告诉就是别再哭鼻子了，赶紧再投别的杂志吧，投之前请按照拒稿意见好好地修改你的文章，避免因为同样的问题被拒稿。</p>

<p>如果审稿人错了如何办？</p>

<p>审稿人不是上帝，也会犯错误。有时他们只是不仔细，你懂的，有可能是学生审的，不要写成“if the referee had bothered to read our paper” 之类的，可以写“we agree that this is an important point and we have already addressed it on page A, paragraph B, line C”.有时就是审稿人犯二了，附和他们是一件很傻的事情，这时候，把证据列出来就好了，杂志社主编会还你一个公道。</p>

<p>如果审稿人对你有歧视如何办？</p>

<p>这时候给杂志社写邮件，抱怨下这个问题，并要求重新送审。</p>

<p>The dreaded “reduce the paper by 30%” request（以及类似这种情况）</p>

<p>这个过程还是很痛苦的，因为你会觉得丢弃任何一部分都很心痛，这时候可以找个朋友来帮忙（针对有选择障碍的小伙伴），看下哪一部分的内容要去掉，另外，温馨提示，前言和讨论是比较好删字的地方。</p>

<p>原文出处<a href="http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzA3ODU1NjUyNw==&amp;mid=208389651&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=393a45ea966160a74f04d6f75bf147c3&amp;scene=5#rd">论文返修那些事儿，你都明白么</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[论文返修模板]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/21/response-letter-template/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-21T16:24:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/21/response-letter-template</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>提供论文返修的几类模板：</p>

<h3>例 1：</h3>

<p>Dear Prof. XXXX,</p>

<p>Thank you very much for your letter and the comments from the referees about our
paper submitted to XXXX (MS Number XXXX).</p>

<p>We have checked the manuscript and revised it according to the comments. We submit
here the revised manuscript as well as a list of changes.</p>

<p>If you have any question about this paper, please don’t hesitate to let me know.
Sincerely yours,</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>例 2：</h3>

<p>Dear Editor and Reviewers:</p>

<p>Thank you for your letter and for the reviewers’ comments concerning our manuscript
entitled “Paper Title” (ID: 文章稿号). Those comments are all valuable and very
helpful for revising and improving our paper, as well as the important guiding
significance to our researches. We have studied comments carefully and have made
correction which we hope meet with approval. Revised portion are marked in red in
the paper. The main corrections in the paper and the responds to the reviewer’s
comments are as flowing:</p>

<p>Responds to the reviewer’s comments:</p>

<p>Reviewer #1:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Response to comment: (……简要列出意见……)</p>

<p>Response: ××××××</p></li>
<li><p>Response to comment: (……简要列出意见……)</p>

<p>Response: ××××××
……</p></li>
</ol>


<p>逐条意见回答，切忌一定不能有遗漏</p>

<p>针对不同的问题有下列几个礼貌术语可适当用用：</p>

<pre><code>We are very sorry for our negligence of ……...
We are very sorry for our incorrect writing ……...
It is really true as Reviewer suggested that……
We have made correction according to the Reviewer’s comments.
We have re-written this part according to the Reviewer’s suggestion
As Reviewer suggested that……
Considering the Reviewer’s suggestion, we have ……
</code></pre>

<p>最后特意感谢一下这个审稿人的意见：</p>

<p>Special thanks to you for your good comments.</p>

<p>Reviewer #2:</p>

<pre><code>同上述
</code></pre>

<p>Reviewer #3:</p>

<pre><code> ××××××
</code></pre>

<p>Other changes:</p>

<pre><code>1. Line 60-61, the statements of “……” were corrected as “…………”
2. Line 107, “……” was added
3. Line 129, “……” was deleted
××××××
</code></pre>

<p>We tried our best to improve the manuscript and made some changes in the
manuscript. These changes will not influence the content and framework of the
paper. And here we did not list the changes but marked in red in revised paper.
We appreciate for Editors/Reviewers’ warm work earnestly, and hope that the
correction will meet with approval.</p>

<p>Once again, thank you very much for your comments and suggestions.</p>

<h3>例 3：</h3>

<p>Dear Professor XXX,</p>

<p>Many thanks for your email of 24 Jun 2013, regarding the revision and advice of the
above paper in XXX 杂志. Overall the comments have been fair, encouraging and
constructive. We have learned much from it.</p>

<p>After carefully studying the reviewer’ comments and your advice, we have made
corresponding changes to the paper. Our response of the comments is enclosed.</p>

<pre><code>(1)
(2)
(3)
(4)
(5)
(6)
</code></pre>

<p>Besides the above changes, we have corrected some expression errors.</p>

<p>Thank you very much for the excellent and professional revision of our manuscript.
If you need any other information, please contact me immediately by email. My email
account is <strong><em>, and Tel.is </em></strong>, and Fax is +***.</p>

<p>Yours sincerely,</p>

<h3>例 4：</h3>

<p>Dear Professor XXX,</p>

<p>We very much appreciate the careful reading of our manuscript and valuable
suggestions of the reviewer. We have carefully considered the comments and have
revised the manuscript accordingly.</p>

<p>The manuscript is revised submission (×××－××××) with new line and
page numbers in the text, some grammar and spelling errors had also been corrected.
Furthermore, the relevant regulations had been made in the original manuscript
according to the comments of reviewers, and the major revised portions were marked
in red bold. We also responded point by point to each reviewer comments as listed
below, along with a clear indication of the location of the revision.</p>

<p>Hope these will make it more acceptable for publication.</p>

<p>List of Major Changes:</p>

<pre><code>1).........
2).........
3).........
</code></pre>

<p>Response to Reviewers:</p>

<pre><code>1).........
2).........
3).........
</code></pre>

<h3>例 5：</h3>

<p>Thank you very much for your letter and advice on our manuscript. We have
resubmited new version of graphsin accordance with recommendations of the
technical editor. We have addressed the comments raised by the reviewers, and the
amendments are highlighted in red in the revised manuscript. We hope that the
revision is acceptable and look forward to hearing from you soon.</p>

<p>Below, please find the comments in black, followed by our responses in red.
Exact changes in the manuscript are also presented in red font.</p>

<h3>例 6：</h3>

<p>Dear editors,</p>

<p>Thank you for your kind comments on our manuscript entitled “XX 文章名”. We have
carefully revised the manuscript according to the reviewer’s comments. Based on the
suggestions, we have made an extensive modification on the revised manuscript.
Detailed revision was shown as follows. The changes to our manuscript within the
document were aslo highlighted by using red colored text.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>As to the related articles published in Asian Pacific Journal of Cancer Prevention,
we have always been reading the latest papers that were published in APJCP. In fact, several high-quality papers arouse us great interest before we drafted our manuscript. From our intensive reading of these papers published in APJCP, we get better understanding of the hotspots in breast cancer research. We also get a
wider view of the regulatory networks that contribute to XXXX. For example, one
paper entitled “XXXX” showed that metastasis-related molecules could be
regulated by microRNAs in human tumor metastasis process. This paper led us to
hypothesize that XXX, a metastasis-associated protein, might also be linked to
microRNA regulations in breast cancer. Hence, this paper provided a novel clue
for us to uncover the mechanisms underlying XXXX cancer metastasis. Based on
all these instructive papers, we have herein added these references to our article in
the revised version (please see P6, Line 15; P12, Line17; P14, Line 21-22; P15,
Line 1-4).</p></li>
<li><p>For the reference format within the article, we are sorry for our incorrect citation
format. And in this revised version, we have checked carefully of all the citations.
All citations within the article were formatted into “Family Name et al., Year” for
over two-author papers, or “Family Name, Year” for only one-author papers.</p></li>
<li><p>For the reference format after the text, we also feel sorry for our carelessness.
Previously, we didn’t notice the special format of APJCP. In the revised version,
we have corrected all the reference formats to meet the requirements of APJCP.
All the detailed corrections could be seen in the Reference section in which
changes were marked by red.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Thank you again for your positive comments on our manuscript. APJCP is an
influential journal which aims to improve our understanding of cancer prevention.
From all the papers published in your journal, readers have been learning a lot.
Hopefully, we could have our article been considered of publication in your
journal. Should there been any other corrections we could make, please feel free
to contact us.</p>

<p>Name</p>

<p>Date</p>

<p>此文转载与<a href="http://pan.baidu.com/s/1gdEbG4r">实验室万事屋</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SCI写作不得不说的经典替换词]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/18/sci-replace-words/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-18T00:24:38-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/18/sci-replace-words</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>具体规则如下：</p>

<ul>
<li>individuals, characters, folks 替换 people , persons.</li>
<li>positive, favorable, rosy, promising, perfect, pleasurable, excellent, outstanding, superior 替换 good.</li>
<li>dreadful, unfavorable, poor, adverse, ill 替换 bad（如果bad做表语，可以有be less impressive替换。）</li>
<li>an army of, an ocean of, a sea of, a multitude of, a host of, if not most 替换 many.</li>
<li>a slice of, quiet a few 替换 some.</li>
<li>harbor the idea that, take the attitude that, hold the view that, it is widely shared that, it is universally acknowledged that 替换 think。</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>affair, business, matter 替换 thing.</li>
<li>shared 替换 common .</li>
<li>reap huge fruits 替换 get many benefits.</li>
<li>for my part ,from my own perspective 替换 in my opinion.</li>
<li>Increasing(ly), growing 替换 more and more（注意没有growingly这种形式。所以当修饰名词时用increasing/growing修饰形容词，副词用increasingly.）</li>
<li>little if anything或little or nothing 替换 hardly.</li>
<li>beneficial, rewarding 替换 helpful.</li>
<li>shopper, client, consumer, purchaser 替换 customer.</li>
<li>overwhelmingly, exceedingly, extremely, intensely 替换 very.</li>
<li>hardly necessary, hardly inevitable…替换 unnecessary, avoidable.</li>
<li>indispensable 替换 necessary.</li>
<li>sth appeals to sb, sth exerts a tremendous fascination on sb 替换sb take interest in / sb. be interested in.</li>
<li>capture one&rsquo;s attention 替换 attract one&rsquo;s attention.</li>
<li>facet, demension, sphere 替换 aspet.</li>
<li>be indicative of, be suggestive of, be fearful of 替换 indicate,suggest, fear.</li>
<li>give rise to, lead to, result in, trigger 替换 cause.</li>
<li>There are several reasons behind sth 替换…reasons for sth.</li>
<li>desire 替换 want.</li>
<li>pour attention into 替换 pay attention to.</li>
<li>bear in mind that 替换 remember.</li>
<li>enjoy, possess 替换 have（注意process是过程的意思）。</li>
<li>interaction 替换 communication.</li>
<li>frown on sth 替换 be against , disagree with sth .</li>
<li>as an example 替换 for example, for instance.</li>
<li>next to / virtually impossible 替换 nearly / almost impossible.</li>
<li>regarding / concerning 替换 about.</li>
<li>crucial /paramount 替换 important.</li>
<li>第一（in the first place/the first and foremost）；第二（there is one more point, I should touch on, that…）；第三（the last but not the least）.</li>
<li>assiduous 替换 hard-working.</li>
<li>arduous 替换 difficult.</li>
<li>underdeveloped / financially-challenged 替换poor（因为poor通常含有贬义）.</li>
<li>demonstrate / manifest 替换 show</li>
<li>invariably 替换 always.</li>
<li>perilous / hazardous替换 dangerous.</li>
<li>formidable 替换 difficult</li>
<li>quintessential 替换 typical（举例时常用，例如：a quintessential example should be cited that=for example; for instance）.</li>
<li>distinguished 替换 famous.</li>
<li>feasible 替换 possible.</li>
<li>consequently, accordingly替换 so.</li>
<li>通常，由数据推断出一定的结论，用Results indicate, infer, suggest, imply that……</li>
</ul>


<p>最常见的引述别人观点的词汇</p>

<p>Much of the research  in sexual selection in the last two decades  has examined  how a female’s preference that does not influence her immediate reproductive success can still evolve if it is genetically correlated with another character under direct selection.(不要每次写到研究时总用study，可以用些其它的词汇，比如examine，work。)</p>

<p>Two hypotheses  for female preference evolution—runaway sexual selection and good genes selection—state that  preferences evolve indirectly because they are genetically correlated with male traits that are under direct selection; that is, the preferences themselves are not under direct selection.(在引述别人的观点时，如果不能完全同意，使用state 比show更加中立些。)</p>

<p>Studies of receiver biases suggest  that such analogies might not be broadly applicable.(suggest,又一种较为客观的引述观点的表达方法。)</p>

<p>Burley argued that the preference for red beaks is adaptive because it indicates male health, and this preference is then transferred to leg-band color.(argue,引用别人观点的又一表述。)</p>

<p>According to the anti-monotony hypothesis, habituation plays an important role in the evolution of complex vocalizations in songbirds: Increased song complexity reduces habituation of neighboring males and courting females.(根据…)</p>

<p>Previous studies of acoustic and bioluminescent interactions had emphasized potential advantages to group-signaling organization, such as minimizing predation, preserving species-specific signal characters, or increasing the attractiveness of the group.(带有小小的强调)</p>

<p>48.常见的连接词有，However, also, in addition, consequently, afterwards, moreover, Furthermore, further, although, unlike, in contrast, Similarly, Unfortunately, alternatively, parallel results, In order to, despite, For example, Compared with, other results, thus, therefore……用好连接词能使文章层次清楚，意思明确。比如，叙述有时间顺序的事件或文献，最早的文献可用AA advocated it for the first time.接下来可用Then BB further demonstrated that. 再接下来，可用Afterwards, CC……如果还有，可用More recent studies by DD……</p>

<p>原文地址：<a href="http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MjM5NjI5MTI3Mw==&amp;mid=201597125&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=ba98f6ac64cba9cf33fcc2769675f59b">PETD亚洲善待博士组织</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[学术论文的摘要该怎么写才能吸引眼球]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/14/how-to-write-abstract/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-14T10:36:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/14/how-to-write-abstract</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>大多数科研人员认为简短、精练、简单是在撰写学术论文摘要时要遵循的几个要素，但芝加哥大学（University of Chicago）的研究人员在研究了100万篇学术论文摘要之后发现：长篇幅、辞藻华丽、大量运用专业术语的摘要反而会使论文的引用率更高。</p>

<p>相关研究结果发表在PLoS Computational Biology上，研究表明，常见的写作规则并不适用于科技论文的撰写，这一现象也可能反映了在线搜索对当今科学领域的发展所造成的多方面影响。</p>

<p>该研究的作者之一、芝加哥大学进化生态学教授兼计算研究所研究员Stefano Allesina说道：“有趣的是，我们发现科研人员所引用的内容实际上并不是读者真正想要了解的。这一现象带来的启发是，我们不应该相信那些我们认为理所当然的写作技巧。”</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>在一个指导毕业生如何撰写学术论文摘要的研讨会上，Allesina想知道是否有确凿的证据表明以往被认定的通用写作规则真的有效。于是Allesina和Cody Weinberger（芝大本科生）收集了数百条关于学术论文写作的建议并将这些建议浓缩成十条简单的写作规则，包括：简短、简单、突出新颖性和重要性、亮出自信等。</p>

<p>该校社会学系副教授兼计算研究所高级研究员James Evans也是该研究的作者之一。研究团队收集了一百万篇各学科（包括生物学、化学、地理学和心理学）的学术论文摘要并检测上述法则对论文引用率的影响（与同一期刊中的其他论文进行对比）。例如，检测“简短”规则时，考察的是摘要中单词或句子的数量与论文引用率之间的关系。</p>

<p>分析结果表明，不管是哪种学科，摘要篇幅较短都会导致论文引用率较低，这与之前人们的普遍认知（篇幅越短越好）背道而驰。尽管不被看好，但大量使用形容词、副词、不常见词汇以及突出新颖性和重要性的摘要会大大提高论文引用率。</p>

<p>综上所述，从字面意思上看，似乎只要将摘要写得冗长、复杂、易于检索、自我描述性强就能提高引用率。但实际上研究人员并不推荐这么做。Allesina说道：“如果你完全遵守这些规则，结果又会适得其反。将你所得到的建议打个折扣并且不要盲目遵从我们的建议才是最好的方法。写出好的学术论文没有捷径可走，用心才能写出好作品。”</p>

<p>然而，Evans表示：“在线浏览的时代已经到来，越是复杂的描述就越能吸引眼球，并最终在获得更多关注和赞誉的同时被最大程度的检索到。”</p>

<p>研究人员认为，研究结论同时反映出随着科研人员浏览论文方式的改变（在线浏览逐渐代替了纸质版浏览），科学领域相关的一些模式也在发生改变。许多常用数据库（如PubMed、Web of Science）在用户提交查询请求时只会通过摘要进行检索。从而导致长篇幅、含有较多与论文原文有关的特定词汇的摘要更易被检索到，从而更易被引用。</p>

<p>研究结果侧面表明，学术期刊强制限定摘要字数会在一定程度上对研究人员及其论文产生不利影响。Allesina提议，相比限定字数的方法，对论文全文进行检索会帮助科研人员更有效地检索到想要的信息。</p>

<p>Allesina表示：“我认为对字数限制越严格，引用效果就会越差。在论文几乎不再被打印浏览的当今时代，这样做完全没有必要。”（募格首译，译审：HH Lang）</p>

<p>原文网址：
<a href="http://phys.org/news/2015-05-short-science-abstracts-jargon-hype.html">http://phys.org/news/2015-05-short-science-abstracts-jargon-hype.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
