<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Write | SecDr]]></title>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/categories/write/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://secdr.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-02T00:42:14-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://secdr.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SecDr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SCI写作不得不说的经典替换词]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/18/sci-replace-words/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-18T00:24:38-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/18/sci-replace-words</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>具体规则如下：</p>

<ul>
<li>individuals, characters, folks 替换 people , persons.</li>
<li>positive, favorable, rosy, promising, perfect, pleasurable, excellent, outstanding, superior 替换 good.</li>
<li>dreadful, unfavorable, poor, adverse, ill 替换 bad（如果bad做表语，可以有be less impressive替换。）</li>
<li>an army of, an ocean of, a sea of, a multitude of, a host of, if not most 替换 many.</li>
<li>a slice of, quiet a few 替换 some.</li>
<li>harbor the idea that, take the attitude that, hold the view that, it is widely shared that, it is universally acknowledged that 替换 think。</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>affair, business, matter 替换 thing.</li>
<li>shared 替换 common .</li>
<li>reap huge fruits 替换 get many benefits.</li>
<li>for my part ,from my own perspective 替换 in my opinion.</li>
<li>Increasing(ly), growing 替换 more and more（注意没有growingly这种形式。所以当修饰名词时用increasing/growing修饰形容词，副词用increasingly.）</li>
<li>little if anything或little or nothing 替换 hardly.</li>
<li>beneficial, rewarding 替换 helpful.</li>
<li>shopper, client, consumer, purchaser 替换 customer.</li>
<li>overwhelmingly, exceedingly, extremely, intensely 替换 very.</li>
<li>hardly necessary, hardly inevitable…替换 unnecessary, avoidable.</li>
<li>indispensable 替换 necessary.</li>
<li>sth appeals to sb, sth exerts a tremendous fascination on sb 替换sb take interest in / sb. be interested in.</li>
<li>capture one&rsquo;s attention 替换 attract one&rsquo;s attention.</li>
<li>facet, demension, sphere 替换 aspet.</li>
<li>be indicative of, be suggestive of, be fearful of 替换 indicate,suggest, fear.</li>
<li>give rise to, lead to, result in, trigger 替换 cause.</li>
<li>There are several reasons behind sth 替换…reasons for sth.</li>
<li>desire 替换 want.</li>
<li>pour attention into 替换 pay attention to.</li>
<li>bear in mind that 替换 remember.</li>
<li>enjoy, possess 替换 have（注意process是过程的意思）。</li>
<li>interaction 替换 communication.</li>
<li>frown on sth 替换 be against , disagree with sth .</li>
<li>as an example 替换 for example, for instance.</li>
<li>next to / virtually impossible 替换 nearly / almost impossible.</li>
<li>regarding / concerning 替换 about.</li>
<li>crucial /paramount 替换 important.</li>
<li>第一（in the first place/the first and foremost）；第二（there is one more point, I should touch on, that…）；第三（the last but not the least）.</li>
<li>assiduous 替换 hard-working.</li>
<li>arduous 替换 difficult.</li>
<li>underdeveloped / financially-challenged 替换poor（因为poor通常含有贬义）.</li>
<li>demonstrate / manifest 替换 show</li>
<li>invariably 替换 always.</li>
<li>perilous / hazardous替换 dangerous.</li>
<li>formidable 替换 difficult</li>
<li>quintessential 替换 typical（举例时常用，例如：a quintessential example should be cited that=for example; for instance）.</li>
<li>distinguished 替换 famous.</li>
<li>feasible 替换 possible.</li>
<li>consequently, accordingly替换 so.</li>
<li>通常，由数据推断出一定的结论，用Results indicate, infer, suggest, imply that……</li>
</ul>


<p>最常见的引述别人观点的词汇</p>

<p>Much of the research  in sexual selection in the last two decades  has examined  how a female’s preference that does not influence her immediate reproductive success can still evolve if it is genetically correlated with another character under direct selection.(不要每次写到研究时总用study，可以用些其它的词汇，比如examine，work。)</p>

<p>Two hypotheses  for female preference evolution—runaway sexual selection and good genes selection—state that  preferences evolve indirectly because they are genetically correlated with male traits that are under direct selection; that is, the preferences themselves are not under direct selection.(在引述别人的观点时，如果不能完全同意，使用state 比show更加中立些。)</p>

<p>Studies of receiver biases suggest  that such analogies might not be broadly applicable.(suggest,又一种较为客观的引述观点的表达方法。)</p>

<p>Burley argued that the preference for red beaks is adaptive because it indicates male health, and this preference is then transferred to leg-band color.(argue,引用别人观点的又一表述。)</p>

<p>According to the anti-monotony hypothesis, habituation plays an important role in the evolution of complex vocalizations in songbirds: Increased song complexity reduces habituation of neighboring males and courting females.(根据…)</p>

<p>Previous studies of acoustic and bioluminescent interactions had emphasized potential advantages to group-signaling organization, such as minimizing predation, preserving species-specific signal characters, or increasing the attractiveness of the group.(带有小小的强调)</p>

<p>48.常见的连接词有，However, also, in addition, consequently, afterwards, moreover, Furthermore, further, although, unlike, in contrast, Similarly, Unfortunately, alternatively, parallel results, In order to, despite, For example, Compared with, other results, thus, therefore……用好连接词能使文章层次清楚，意思明确。比如，叙述有时间顺序的事件或文献，最早的文献可用AA advocated it for the first time.接下来可用Then BB further demonstrated that. 再接下来，可用Afterwards, CC……如果还有，可用More recent studies by DD……</p>

<p>原文地址：<a href="http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MjM5NjI5MTI3Mw==&amp;mid=201597125&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=ba98f6ac64cba9cf33fcc2769675f59b">PETD亚洲善待博士组织</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[学术论文的摘要该怎么写才能吸引眼球]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/14/how-to-write-abstract/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-14T10:36:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/14/how-to-write-abstract</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>大多数科研人员认为简短、精练、简单是在撰写学术论文摘要时要遵循的几个要素，但芝加哥大学（University of Chicago）的研究人员在研究了100万篇学术论文摘要之后发现：长篇幅、辞藻华丽、大量运用专业术语的摘要反而会使论文的引用率更高。</p>

<p>相关研究结果发表在PLoS Computational Biology上，研究表明，常见的写作规则并不适用于科技论文的撰写，这一现象也可能反映了在线搜索对当今科学领域的发展所造成的多方面影响。</p>

<p>该研究的作者之一、芝加哥大学进化生态学教授兼计算研究所研究员Stefano Allesina说道：“有趣的是，我们发现科研人员所引用的内容实际上并不是读者真正想要了解的。这一现象带来的启发是，我们不应该相信那些我们认为理所当然的写作技巧。”</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>在一个指导毕业生如何撰写学术论文摘要的研讨会上，Allesina想知道是否有确凿的证据表明以往被认定的通用写作规则真的有效。于是Allesina和Cody Weinberger（芝大本科生）收集了数百条关于学术论文写作的建议并将这些建议浓缩成十条简单的写作规则，包括：简短、简单、突出新颖性和重要性、亮出自信等。</p>

<p>该校社会学系副教授兼计算研究所高级研究员James Evans也是该研究的作者之一。研究团队收集了一百万篇各学科（包括生物学、化学、地理学和心理学）的学术论文摘要并检测上述法则对论文引用率的影响（与同一期刊中的其他论文进行对比）。例如，检测“简短”规则时，考察的是摘要中单词或句子的数量与论文引用率之间的关系。</p>

<p>分析结果表明，不管是哪种学科，摘要篇幅较短都会导致论文引用率较低，这与之前人们的普遍认知（篇幅越短越好）背道而驰。尽管不被看好，但大量使用形容词、副词、不常见词汇以及突出新颖性和重要性的摘要会大大提高论文引用率。</p>

<p>综上所述，从字面意思上看，似乎只要将摘要写得冗长、复杂、易于检索、自我描述性强就能提高引用率。但实际上研究人员并不推荐这么做。Allesina说道：“如果你完全遵守这些规则，结果又会适得其反。将你所得到的建议打个折扣并且不要盲目遵从我们的建议才是最好的方法。写出好的学术论文没有捷径可走，用心才能写出好作品。”</p>

<p>然而，Evans表示：“在线浏览的时代已经到来，越是复杂的描述就越能吸引眼球，并最终在获得更多关注和赞誉的同时被最大程度的检索到。”</p>

<p>研究人员认为，研究结论同时反映出随着科研人员浏览论文方式的改变（在线浏览逐渐代替了纸质版浏览），科学领域相关的一些模式也在发生改变。许多常用数据库（如PubMed、Web of Science）在用户提交查询请求时只会通过摘要进行检索。从而导致长篇幅、含有较多与论文原文有关的特定词汇的摘要更易被检索到，从而更易被引用。</p>

<p>研究结果侧面表明，学术期刊强制限定摘要字数会在一定程度上对研究人员及其论文产生不利影响。Allesina提议，相比限定字数的方法，对论文全文进行检索会帮助科研人员更有效地检索到想要的信息。</p>

<p>Allesina表示：“我认为对字数限制越严格，引用效果就会越差。在论文几乎不再被打印浏览的当今时代，这样做完全没有必要。”（募格首译，译审：HH Lang）</p>

<p>原文网址：
<a href="http://phys.org/news/2015-05-short-science-abstracts-jargon-hype.html">http://phys.org/news/2015-05-short-science-abstracts-jargon-hype.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[如何在国际学术期刊上发表论文]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/05/how-to-publish-in-top-journals/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-05T12:24:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/05/how-to-publish-in-top-journals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[摘要]将论文都投在一流期刊上是风险很大的；将论文都寄到低质量的期刊也不是好的选择，一但论文被接受，你就会感到后悔。一个人的简历中应包括一些一流期刊的论文。发表的质量也是很重要的。</p>

<p>1.目的</p>

<p>决定一片论文是否可以发表的最重要因素是论文中所阐述思想的好坏。实际中，非实质性的因素，如论文的包装，也会成为论文是否发表的影响因素。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>1.1.为什么期刊的接受率这么低</p>

<p>提交给国际有影响的期刊论文，一般只有1/3的作者能够受到略微积极的反馈；其他则都为否定。如果有两个匿名评审人评审一篇论文，那么一篇平均质量的论文被两个评审人同时接受的可能性只有11%。计算机和激光打印的发展，导致论文数量迅速增加，一流期刊积存了大量的论文。</p>

<p>期刊的主编变得非常谨慎，他们宁愿拒绝一篇可能是高质量的论文，也不愿承担接受一篇低质量论文的风险。在国际学术期刊上发表论文，靠运气并不能成功，必须依靠实力，并有冒险的精神。在国际学术期刊的评审中，评审人的意见并不都是等同的，有名的评审人的意见份量更重要。因此，你应该了解哪一个评审人更加重要。当一篇论文被拒之后，总编更关注的是论文消极一面，而不是积极的一面。如果能消除论文中的缺点，那末再次提交成功的可能性就会提高。</p>

<p>1.2.为什么你的论文的接受率这样低</p>

<p>也许由于种族、性别、国籍或学历等原因，你受到歧视。例如，如果一所大学的期刊为自己的教师预留出一半的版面，那么，如果你是这所大学的教师，论文的接受率就会提高很多。</p>

<p>2.发表的一般策略</p>

<p>2.1.研究成果的组合要多样化</p>

<p>接受决定的平均等待时间是3年；拒绝决定的平均等待时间是6-8个月；在你学术生涯的起步阶段，生存比辉煌更重要；美国从教的前5-6年，如果每篇发表成果在评估时权重相同，那么，使你的成果组合多样化非常重要，应争取使研究的题目越多越好；如果在某一方面的发表有出色的表现，把研究兴趣转向其他方面之前，应加倍努力树立自己在这一方面的名声。</p>

<p>在一个非常窄的问题上发表篇论的文风险很大，就像把所有的鸡蛋放在一个篮子里一样。持续研究一个窄的问题而不能发表，是一个不详的兆头。</p>

<p>2.2.专注于一个或两个专业领域</p>

<p>通常，一个人选择的专业领域不应超过两个，研究的规模经济一般要求学者们将全部注意力放在一个领域里。在一个专业领域里，选择两到三个题目，勤奋耕耘，直至发表几篇论文。如果针对某一个题目，3年没有发表一篇论文，此时应该考虑更换题目。</p>

<p>2.3.从博士论文中产生出1至2篇论文</p>

<p>一篇博士论文，通常要投入了2年甚至更长的时间；努力从博士论文重要的章节中派生出几篇论文；这比从头开始写新的论文要来的容易的多；同导师合作，推出你的论文。</p>

<p>2.4.手中要有几篇论文供周转</p>

<p>如果一流期刊的接受率为15%，那么一个人手中应有7篇论文不断处在被评审状态，这样才能保证每年有一篇论文被锁定的期刊接受；如果想在任教后的前5年发表10篇论文，那么必须有约12篇论文要不断处在被评审状态；对于一个没有终身教职的人，应该有约6篇论文不断处在被评审状态。</p>

<p>2.5.几个好的观点不要放在一篇论文里</p>

<p>把两个好的观点分放在两篇论文中。不要把关于某一问题的所有观点都放在一篇论文里，保留一些给今后的论文。如果论文的长度超过15页，被接受的概率呈几何级数下降。如果将一个题目分解成两篇论文，一篇论文被接受的概率会超过一倍，接受的速度也会加快。</p>

<p>用x表示论文的长度， p表示论文被接受的概率，则：</p>

<p>P(x/2) = 2 p(x) + a， a>o. x&lt;15页</p>

<p>A包括的因素有：</p>

<p>主编喜欢短论文；</p>

<p>评审人发现数学错误的概率降低；</p>

<p>评审人错误理解论文内容的概率也降低.</p>

<p>2.6.向不同期刊投稿</p>

<p>将论文都投在一流期刊上是风险很大的；将论文都寄到低质量的期刊也不是好的选择，一但论文被接受，你就会感到后悔。一个人的简历中应包括一些一流期刊的论文。发表的质量也是很重要的。如果论文质量相同，将3篇论文投到3种不同的期刊要优于都投到一个期刊。</p>

<p>2.7.表述清楚</p>

<p>假设和结果要解释清楚；如果有许多假设，将它们放在一起，不要分放在段落中，也不要造成让评审人四处找符号含义的局面。第一次使用的符号要定义清楚，否则评审人会不满意，发表的可能性从而降低；论文结论中要清楚地表陈述论文对现有文献有哪些贡献。</p>

<p>2.8.经常浏览最新期刊</p>

<p>紧跟文献的当前变化(如使用EconLit)。利用关键词核实相同或类似的题目，，他人是否已经写过。不要重复他人已经做的工作，这可以节省许多时间。</p>

<p>订购一些所在领域的专业期刊，不要订购综合性期刊。综合性期刊不能最有效地提供你所在领域的信息来源，同你研究者兴趣直接相关的论文正变得越来越少。其他期刊可以利用图书馆，一旦一篇论文被接受，Social Science Research Network会刊登出相关的消息，这样可以了解到某一领域的最新发表。</p>

<p>2.9. 提交前在研讨会上宣读论文</p>

<p>在地区性、全国和国际研讨会上宣读自己的论文，也许可以获得非常有价值的反馈建议。是认识同行的一个极好机会。在自己所在的系里宣读论文效果不明显，除了一流的院系，大多数学系只有20甚至更少的教师，他们一般不熟悉你的研究，也缺少提出带有根本性建议的能力。</p>

<p>2.10. 不要将未发表的论文送给陌生人</p>

<p>如果这样做，也许可以暂时出名，但随后会付出代价；一些人可能剽窃你的观点，并先于你提交一篇类似的论文；在一个大家都彼此认识的圈子里，散发论文是可以的。</p>

<p>2.11. 越挫越勇</p>

<p>一般收到拒绝频率会超过接受，这是很自然的。脸皮要厚，学会作一个失败者。如果不能接受拒绝的打击，最好不要向期刊提交论文。一篇好的论文，至少可以在高质量的期刊有3次发表的机会。如果在一个月内，对一篇被拒绝的论文不做任何处理，你很可能会对它丧失兴趣，因此，要抓紧时间采取行动。</p>

<p>2.12. 认识100个所在领域发表最活跃的人</p>

<p>一个领域中，可能成为你的论文评审人的数量大约是100左右。拟定一份本领域最活跃的学者的名单，用5年的时间全部认识他们。每年至少两次在专业研讨会上宣读论文，或至少参加两次这样的研讨会。</p>

<p>本文节选自Kwan Choi所写的《How to Publish in Top Journals》</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[如何选择和阅读研究文献]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/04/how-to-select-and-read-paper/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-04T09:39:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/04/how-to-select-and-read-paper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我们很多的时候，闷在实验室闭门造车，实在不如稍抽出一点时间看看文献，看看别人是否有同样的困惑。我们的大老板说，要想有成绩别无他法只有读，读，大量的读文献，尤其国外的。</p>

<h3>阅读文献的来源</h3>

<p>A精研数据库，对于文献数据库和专业数据库应该深入研究。重要的如ISI，Medline,Ncbi等了。因人而异添加数据库到你的收藏夹。</p>

<p>B做一个课题首先是要看专利的！！这是我的经验之谈。通过研读专利正文，可以体会申请人的研发思路；研读专利权要求，可以少走弯路，还可以找出未覆盖的漏洞，进一步提出自己的专利；有的专利还有参考文献，可以了解这个专利的来龙去脉。</p>

<p>C了解与自己研究方向有关的机构,密切关注在该研究领域和方向的顶尖group所发表的论文并认真研读。对于本研究领域的国际领袖人物和实验室，应该多花一点时间去研究他们的主页。</p>

<p>D可以在google上免费订购你所感兴趣的alert,他24小时更新，会不间断的向你信箱发送网上出现该话题的文章。</p>

<p>E经常上网看看最新的资讯说不准会激发你一时的灵感。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>F定期读几篇cell ，nature,science还是很重要的，不要认为和自己专业无关的就不关心，其实目前生物医学界的许多方法和思路是相通的，nature,science上最新的方法用到自己的领域上完全可能豁然开朗。</p>

<p>G对于你从事的领域的重点杂志（NO.1）（&lt;&lt;国外医学>>各个分册每其都有许多可读的综述，注意自己专业的核心刊的专辑,增刊,很重要!），应该是每一期的每一篇文章都阅读一下，然后是重点阅读。如果没有那么多的时间，至少每篇的TITLE &amp; ABSTRACT应该阅读的。</p>

<p>H特别要注意中文综述文章后的英文参考文献，可以用回顾性的方法查找该问题的最初起源及奠基性文章。 查阅大量外文文献，然后从文献的文献再去查找，如此往复循环，你的idea不知不觉中就被启发开来。我们老板说过，看文献，最重要，最有权威，也最有深度的是什么，就是你查找的文献的文献。 读文献一定要注意文章后面列出的参考文献,按图索骥,就很易找到更多文献,而且被引次数越多的越重要!!通过搜索参考文献的作者,期刊目次找到更多该领域的文章。</p>

<h3>如何查找阅读文献</h3>

<p>课题未定：</p>

<p>我很是崇拜神经所蒲教授的观点，阅读文献从教科书开始-找到自己最感兴趣的问题，查找相关综述，你会发现书上一些所谓的成熟观点，在综述中是“推测”，然后找原始文献，你回发现，有许多实验证据是在当时条件不够的情况下的初步探索。如果你发现这样的问题，一个流行观点没有使用目前、最新技术验证，你去验证一下，回有两种结果：证实，那你就是用最新技术验证一个很正确的观点，给他提供了新证据，这属于好工作，另外你发现前人的观点有错误，那你就找到一条将来的科研方向，继续做下去，搞定！</p>

<p>一定得知道自己所作的方向现在世界上是个怎样的研究现状&mdash;做到了何种程度,还有那些关键问题急待解决.这一点对于自己找题目的战友,我觉得尤为重要!</p>

<p>课题已定：</p>

<p>首先要做的是寻找权威杂志上相关研究领域权威人士撰写的综述类文章。这类文章信息量大，论述精辟，读后不但有助于掌握相关研究的重点和焦点内容，而且能帮助我们掌握研究领域的大方向和框架，哪些人、哪个大学或研究所、在哪个方向比较强等等；其次是泛读摘要，挑选最相关的进行精读。精读文章同时做笔记和标记是非常关键的，因为好文章可能每读一遍就有不同的收获，每次的笔记加上心得最后总结起来就会对自己大有帮助；再次是针对不同的需要对论文进行泛读和跳读。</p>

<p>涉足一些和专业有点瓜葛但有相当距离的领域。</p>

<p>我一般研读相关文献的程序是：</p>

<p>1、对该领域有较多介绍的中文成书（资料一般是比较老，如果是新书通常汇集了最近5到10年 的主要研究内容和结果）读后可以对这个领域发展历史和近期状况有个全面的了解，一些专门的术语和英文单词也有了概念。</p>

<p>2、根据研究内容通查最近3年的中文期刊，主要是通过看综述了解最近进展和一些国外发表文章的人名和期刊名，还有国内做到什么程度了，为请该类项目打个基础。你可以知道国内那些同行在做这工作.如果实验中碰到一些具体的细节问题的话,你可以联系他们,这便可以使你避免走不必要的弯路。</p>

<p>3、根据上面的学习掌握的专业词汇，人名，期刊名查国外文献。我的体会是，如果那个领域和原来专业距离比较远，那么一来就去查外文的文献往往找不出好东东，特别是一些关键词常有臆断的情况，导致检索效果不好。</p>

<p>我觉得对于自己要研究的不熟悉的内容，例如某种疾病，那么你得首先翻翻中文教科书，要对这一种疾病有一个大概的了解，这样在你以后阅读文献时会很有帮助。</p>

<p>然后，在上网查一些你的老板或你自己想要做的题目的相关方面的中文综述，也算是对教科书内容的补充。同时也让你有可能触及到国内目前的此方面的前沿。</p>

<p>这时候，你可以开始阅读一些外文的综述，看一看国外的研究情况和进展。或许，此时你会对你想要研究什么有更进一步的了解。接下来，就可以阅读一些国外的原始论著，它将会告诉你如何去完成你要研究的题目。等到文献量积累到一定程度后就可以开始你的课题了。但千万别忘了，时刻关注你正在研究的相关内容研究进展，它可能会给你的课题新的补充。</p>

<p>最后一条，看文献，编上号，做好笔记。
对于一个尚不熟悉领域的课题,先找相关的综述,综述是了解该领域最快的途径,因为教材具有滞后性,而论著又偏重于某一点,优秀的综述可以作教材读的。</p>

<h3>读文献的顺序</h3>

<p>当然还是从中文到外文，毕竟，中文是自己的母语，容易看懂，也容易有成就感。</p>

<p>文章内容是从综述到论著。一般花上一两个小时，可以查一堆文献，先把它们的摘要整理出来，甚至打印出来，根据摘要，可以初步判断哪些是自己决定要的。然后再到网上找全文，找不到再去图书馆，还找不到就发E-mail给国外的同学，一般都能获取到。对于自己感兴趣的问题，不仅要看原文，还要看它的参考文献，一般深追上几篇文章，对于想了解的问题也就知道个大概了。在读文章的过程中，当然要做些笔记，建一个word文档，做些复制拷贝的工作便可，这样做的好处是，回头就不必再花好多时间去找你的论据或论点。</p>

<h3>如何阅读文献</h3>

<p>看文章时做笔记</p>

<p>阅读笔记本可按不同的内容进行分类摘录，如:进展,研究方法，实验方法，研究结果等，并可加上自己的批注。对于笔记要定期总结（总结过去已经做过什么&mdash;&mdash;-做到心中有数；现在进展到什么程度&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;做到知己知彼；从中发现别人的优点和不足。预测将来的热点和发展方向&mdash;&mdash;&ndash;才能准确出击，找到自己的方向和目标！）。我们要着眼于将自己的成果往SCI上发，所以对一些经典的陈述，要有选择性的标记并记下来。另外，有的时候想到的思路，闪过的想法，作笔记记下来，随时查一查，可能时间久了自然就有新的看法。</p>

<p>勤思考</p>

<p>不单单是了解别人做了什么，还要考虑别人没做什么，或者他的实验能不能和他的结论吻合，数据可不可靠等等。</p>

<p>用图表的方式将作者的整个逻辑画出来，逐一推敲，抱着一种挑的心态想。</p>

<p>带着挑剔的眼神去读文献，不要盲目崇拜，有些东东自己作作，发现并不是那么回事，自己要动手，自己更要动脑。</p>

<p>看文献中懂得抓重点，找思路。主要是学习别人的IDEA。也就是看了文献问几个问题，文章的技术突破口在那里。比如一大堆专利讲了很多种分离方法，关键不是看它先做什么后做什么，而是想这个分离方法的依据是什么，为什么人家会想到这个方法，是不是还有其他方面的物性可以利用为分离的依据。</p>

<p>多与人交流</p>

<p>和导师谈谈你的想法，交流一下各自所了解的所在领域某一方向的研究进展；与相关方向的牛人谈谈，对自己的启发要比看文献大的多。</p>

<p>不仅与本领域的牛人交谈，还抓住机会与其他领域的牛人交谈，牛人的一句话，有时你读半年书都读不来的。特别是其他领域的牛人，他没准就给你一个金点子，特别是在中国，牛人一般对外行人不怎么保守。</p>

<p>集体讨论非常必要，找几个志同道合的人一起，文献人人都有一份，每人分工读不同的文献，然后大家坐到一起。顺序开讲，互相讨论。这样，文献量是不是就成N次方增加了！！！</p>

<p>比较阅读</p>

<p>观点相反的论文可以参照来读，品味一下双方的观点。还有就是与原著同时发表的其他专家的述评、原著发表后的读者质疑，都应当和原著一起读。比较一下，就可以看到自己的差距了。</p>

<p>读论文的时候最有意思的事情是发现“一稿两投”。我的意思是不少作者把同一科研数据写成相似主题的不同论文，或是在前面的基础上又有了新的发展变化。这时，如果你的课题与此类似，你的好运也就来了。因为能通过深入比较这几篇文章的异同，发现作者（或科研小组）对同一组数据的不同看法、思路的演变，或者发现作者本想隐藏的“真正”方法。我就是在分析了同一科研小组的类似实验后，迅速发现自己实验失败的关键原因，短时间内成功完成动物模型制作的，为进一步实验打下了基础。</p>

<p>做技术的要善于比较和发现，一些技术含量高文献，不可能把要点都报道出来，中文如此，英文也是如此。比如一篇专利中有很多的Sample,而每个的条件或配方都不同，这时要多比较几个同类文献，看其共同点在那里。这点在制药和表面活性剂行业还是要注意的。</p>

<p>全面参考国外文献。一定要清楚,国外文献也有一些不可信的文章;另外一种现象就是关于重点的关键的东西他会略去不写,有时一些细节的东西他也不会写的.问题是各人省略的关键和细节不尽相同,你便从对比中发现他们研究的脉络和问题的关键所在。</p>

<p>单篇文章阅读顺序及侧重</p>

<p>论文阅读顺序：
1. 摘要 引文 引用的主要信息 研究背景。
2. 图表 了解主要数据和解释。
3. 讨论和结论 将图表和结论联系起来 根据图表判断结论是否恰当。
4. 结果 详细阅读结果 看数据是如何得到的，又是如何分析的。
5. 材料和方法 详细阅读材料和实验方法 看实验是如何进行的。
6. 讨论和结果 进一步掌握论文，注意讨论中的关于从已知的知识和研究如何解释本文获得的结果。另外对于论文中大量的图表来说，当你能够重新画出这张图，并且能用自己的语言解说这张图，表明就读懂了。</p>

<p>一篇论文中最重要的部分依次是: 图表，讨论，文字结果，方法。现在生命科学中的杂志对图表的要求都很高，必须做到仅通过阅读图表及其说明文字即能把握文章的方法、结果，再结合读者自己的原有知识，就大概知道其implication了。这符合现代人必须在最短的时间内把握最必要的信息的要求。因此，在某个领域做了一段工作后，定期查新得到的文章只须看摘要、图表即可，个别涉及新方法或突破性结果，再看讨论，文字结果和方法。这也提示我们在写外文文章时，注重图表及其说明文字，做到形象化、信息最大化。</p>

<p>自己熟悉的领域</p>

<p>最省事的是只看摘要，因为依靠背景知识通过摘要即可大致勾勒出文章内容，但有时这是不够的，相对省事的方法是细看摘要，略读前言，再看结果中的图表，最后读一下自己感兴趣的讨论部分。但如果文章对自己很有意义，那就应该通读全文了。</p>

<p>如在寻找课题阶段，重点读讨论和结论以及展望，在课题设计阶段，主要是材料和方法。若只需了解一下该研究的思路,可选取摘要及引文与结论进行泛读。 个人的经验是尽量去把握作者的研究思路，然后是学习他们的分析方法，最后是学习写作技巧和写作语言方式等。</p>

<p>文章的讨论部分真是很重要，如果时间稍微充裕点，建议研读和模仿牛人paper的讨论部分。不同的人对同样的数据可能有不同看法和分析方式，图表的趋势解析，论据的组合，都是非常看功力的部分，我们老板经常说：如果某篇SCI级别的文章让我们这些菜鸟来写，可能发国内核心都非常困难。</p>

<p>我觉的最重要的是理解讨论中的精髓，这是作者idea创新性以及与旧有的实验结果比较的关键部分，可以看出作者设计此实验的思路，在作出比较以后，对自己的课题会有很大启发。</p>

<p>除了文章内容，还要学习人家写作的方法和格式等等，比如同样一个观点，别人有可能表达的很地道，同样一个图表，别人做的很漂亮，尤其是老外的文章，给老外投稿，人家的修改意见要求文字通俗易懂，带有一定的科普性，即使不是本专业的人，也能大致看懂；然后还要求多用简单句，能用简单句说明的问题，就不要用复合句，在同一句子中，最好不要让同一个词汇或短语重复出现 &hellip;&hellip;</p>

<p>最后想说的一点，就是注意中文和外文的互相印证，注意一些专业词汇的翻译，注意用词的恰当和简洁，久而久之，对于提高自己的外语水平，也是大有裨益的。</p>

<p>文献追踪的重要性</p>

<p>在现在这个信息时代，往往你的idea别人也会有不谋而和的时候，所以要特别关注这个领域的最新动向。在抓紧使自己出成果的同时，随时根据有可能出现的“撞车”进行调整，做到心中有数。和自己课题相关的文章一定要勤跟踪，现在国外的科研做得又快又漂亮，我们在做到心中有数的情况下，可以扬长避短，作出新东西来。了解与自己研究方向有关的机构,密切关注在该研究领域和方向的顶尖group（研究团体以及牛人）所发表的论文。对于数据库的定题、定词地定期搜索，这样才能保证你不丢下每一篇重要的文献。文献总要紧密结合自己的方向为方向服务!</p>

<p>已定课题的实施</p>

<p>1、得到一个大概方向。
2、查相关中文综述，查看国内有谁或哪个单位在做相关内容。
3、查外文综述，比较一下，毕竟外文可能会更详尽一些，看看大家对什么感兴趣。
4、查较关键的参考文献，注意杂志和作者的权威性、引用次数
5、重检相关全文，注意研究方法、和技术路线，讨论中存在什么问题
6、根据本人所能控制的资金和本地技术资源考虑我能做什么，怎么做
7、再进一步紧缩范围，有一个框架图
8、根据框架图再进一步查外文原文以明细节。</p>

<p>实验思路永远要走在实验之前，凡事想好再作，一定没错！</p>

<p>在实验方案的设计和实验细节方面一定要多下功夫,力求用实验室最成熟的技术.对于一些自己没有做过的实验,一定要吃透原理,再下手不迟,切记盲目.有些实验若自己实验室确有困难,可以考虑合作,因为一个人不可能在短时间内把什么都做好.我的体会是,有时就需要请教专家!</p>

<p>作者：往北走 来源：知乎</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Tips for Academics]]></title>
    <link href="http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/04/storytelling-101-writing-tips-for-academics/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-04T01:00:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://secdr.github.io/2015/05/04/storytelling-101-writing-tips-for-academics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Little did I know that a Ph.D. in computer science would teach me more about how to write than any other previous experience I’d had.  Indeed, research isn’t only about making new discoveries, but also about expressing those discoveries so that other people can appreciate them and their significance.</p>

<p>Below, I’ll present some thoughts on writing that I’ve picked up over the years and continually aim (and encourage students) to put into practice. I’ll focus on story-telling, presentation, and efficiency: how to write your paper so that it clearly, cleanly, and efficiently tells a good story.</p>

<p>What this post is not about.  At least in this post, I won’t write about grammar—there is too much English grammar to cover in a single post, and there are plenty of good courses one can take to learn grammar.  I also won’t talk about style (common phrases) or usage (e.g., commonly misused words).  For now, my only advice on the topic of learning English grammar and style—both for native speakers and foreigners—is to read daily.  Reading the New York Times, or The Economist are great places to start: the writing is generally of high quality, and you’ll also have something interesting to talk about outside of the lab.  I have the impression that foreign students can tend towards reading their local news from home; that’s understandable, but I would encourage those students to also read periodicals and publications that are written in the style of English that people are used to reading in the Western world (indeed, English in different parts of the world has different tones, styles, idioms, and turns of phrase).</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Why Does Writing Well Matter?</h3>

<p>Writing is part and parcel of the research process.  Writing communicates your research results, and—perhaps contrary to intuition—writing well is even more important when the results that one wants to present are “strong” (after all, if the results are that great, you should want as many people as possible to benefit from understanding them).  But writing isn’t just something that happens at when the research is “done”; rather, writing should occur throughout the course of a research project.  Writing and thinking are tightly coupled—writing is a reflection of our own thoughts, and writing well can actually sometimes clarify our own thinking about a problem and lead us to a solution.</p>

<p>Communicating your results. A research finding or discovery that others cannot understand or appreciate is as good as no discovery in the first place.  A well-written paper with a half-baked idea that people can understand and appreciate will often be accepted to a conference over a paper with a (possibly) stronger result that nobody can understand or appreciate.  Cynics may dismiss this as “unfair”, as “laziness” on the reviewer’s part for not reading the details thoroughly, or as “accepting a paper because it was well-written” (insinuating that the results themselves might not be that strong).  The fact of the matter is that none of this matters: Independently of the quality of the research, the results must be written well, or people will not be able to appreciate the value of your work. Writing well is perhaps one of the most important skills that budding researchers must attain; it is equally important as learning how to conduct the research.</p>

<p>Clarifying your own thinking.  Writing is a reflection of your thinking.  You should never be content with vague language or imprecise descriptions.  Muddy writing often reflects muddy thinking.  An attempt to write down a concept, idea, or solution can actually help you realize that you don’t know what you are talking about!  (And, help you crystallize your thinking.)  You may have had the experience of realizing you don’t understand something as well as you thought you did when someone asks you to explain something and you have trouble.  Writing achieves the same effect: as you attempt to write something down, you may realize that you don’t know why you are working on something, why a particular phenomenon appears, and so forth.  If you don’t force yourself to try to write down your explanations and observations, you may never discover that you don’t know what you’re doing until it’s too late.  Therefore, start writing early in the course of a research project.  Most of the early text you write may not find its way into the final version of the paper, but taking the time to express your ideas on paper can help you crystallize your thoughts and guide your research.</p>

<h3>Tell Me a Story</h3>

<p>Every paper should tell a story.  For a given research result, there are many stories that a paper could tell, and it’s important to think about what the story should be.  This decision should be made early on in the writing process.  The story can be changed later on, to match the strongest results in the paper, or if the context for the research changes (for example, sometimes when working on a research problem, people can find it necessary to re-formulate the problem that they are solving).  But, it’s always good to figure out a story before you go too far down the path.</p>

<p>Determining the Big Picture: Composition and “Flow”. Composition is the structure and flow of your paper writeup, and how individual paragraphs fit together.  When people talk about the “flow” of a piece of writing, they’re talking about composition: how sentences flow together to form paragraphs, how paragraphs flow together to form sections, and how sections flow together to form a paper.  Composition (or “flow”) is the most important aspect of technical writing.  I’ve found that reviewers (and readers) are often forgiving of the occasional grammatical error, especially if a paper was written by non-native English speakers.  The human brain is pretty good at applying “error correction” on grammar.  Correcting “flow”, on the other hand, is extremely hard for a reader to do.  Often, the reader will complain that they “can’t understand where [the paper] is going” and simply give up.  Grammar is also easier to teach (and learn) than composition because there are fixed rules for grammar; composition is more of an art form, and it does involve a bit of intuition.  It involves thinking about the big picture, the story that you want to tell, and how the pieces fit together.  It takes practice to develop intuition for composition, and I’ve found that native English speakers are not necessarily any better at composition than foreigners are (that’s good news for Ph.D. students coming from abroad: the playing field is actually more level than it appears).  Even though composition is a bit of an art form, I’ve found that the following tips can be incredibly helpful for improving flow:</p>

<p>Build the scaffolding before filling in the details. Write sections and topic sentences first.  There is always the temptation to simply jump in and start writing full paragraphs.  This rarely ends well.  Nobody would build a house before first drawing plans.  After the plans comes a foundation, and scaffolding.  Only after the structure is in place can many of the details be filled in.  You should think about writing a paper in the same way: before you can fill in the details, you need to figure out how you want the paper to read when its done; this is your outline.  Start at a high level, by outlining sections.  Once you have an outline of sections, you can begin to slowly fill in more details: outline each paragraph within a section by writing only the topic sentence for the paragraph.  See whether your story makes sense if you read each topic sentence in sequence.  Your “paper” should roughly make sense if you read these topic sentences in sequence (in fact, some reviewers or readers may try to read your paper in exactly this fashion, by skimming topic sentences!).  If reading your topic sentences in sequence doesn’t make sense, something is wrong with your flow.   Determining which topic sentences to write takes a bit of practice, but I find that making a bulleted list of points that you want to include in the section and then clustering those points into related points and topics can help identify the topics you want to cover (and, hence, the topic sentences you want to write).  If you find that the topics you want to cover are not all related to one another, you may need to create additional subsections.  Once you have topic sentences, you can fill in paragraphs, which are groups of closely (and logically) related sentences.  If your sentences aren’t closely related, they don’t belong in the same paragraph and you may need to consider adding a new topic (and topic sentence).
Assess balance and budget pages accordingly.  Once you have your outline, it’s important to budget pages, to figure out how much you plan to write about each topic.  Topics of equal importance or equal relevance should receive “balanced” coverage in the paper.  If your system has two components of relatively equal importance, then the sections covering those components should be of approximately equal length in the paper.  Once you have your outline (from the previous step), you can assess how much space you want to budget for each point.  If some points in a section are more important than others (and hence require more page budget), you can go back and think about how to re-balance your writeup (e.g., by creating a new devoted section to the topic that’s more important, shortening or eliminating the less important point, and so forth).
Follow convention.  Continuing the analogy of a house or building, many designs follow convention: a restroom in a restaurant is often in the back.  A powder room in a house is often near the front door.  These common “design patterns” make life easier for us when we visit a new building or house.  Similarly, your reader is a visitor of your thought process.  A reader who has read (and written) many research papers will similarly expect the structure of your paper to follow certain conventions.  These conventions differ by field: some fields write papers completely in the passive voice, whereas others use active voice.  Some fields prefer related work sections at the beginning of the paper, and others prefer related work at the end.  Some fields expect an introduction that spends time framing the problem, and others expect an introduction that starts with a clear statement of the main result.  There may be an expectation of (or aversion) to mathematics in the main line of the paper.  Within a section, people may expect the introduction to flow in a particular way (in computer science, Jim Kurose’s description of how to write an intro is the best example I’ve seen for writing a conventional paper introduction).
Signpost your paper.  Even if your paper plan and outline make perfect sense to you, the reader doesn’t start out “on the same page” as you.  Even if the builders have built a house completely according to the blueprints, even if the design of the house follows convention, visitors still typically appreciate an explanation of where the bathroom is.  The reader needs instructions for how to read the paper and a clear view for how the paper and story will proceed.  Signposts throughout the paper help the reader understand how the paper is organized.  Examples of signposts include: an outline of the paper at the end of the introduction (“The rest of this paper proceeds as follows.”), a preamble to each section (“In this section, we discuss…”), declarative subsection titles, and (within reason) bold paragraph headings (such as those in this blog post).
Make a Good Impression
A reader forms an impression about your research based on your presentation of the work.  Just as people quickly form first impressions about other people that may be difficult to subsequently correct, your reader will quickly form a first impression of your work based on a quick read of the title, abstract, and introduction and perhaps a quick skim through other parts of the paper.  Therefore, it is important to make a good impression by writing a clear abstract and introduction (and also ensuring that the rest of the paper also is commensurate with the impression that you create).</p>

<p>Spend a lot of time on your introduction; start early.  The introduction summarizes the story of your paper (now, it should be doubly clear why you need a story!) and is the most important part of your paper.  Many people won’t read past the introduction, even if they find the work interesting.  Yet, if people don’t understand your “story” (the problem you’re solving, its importance, and your approach to solving it), they will never make it past the introduction into the details of the paper.  There are two schools of thought for writing the introduction: if you write it first, you ensure that you have a clear story.  If you write it last, then your introduction will clearly reflect the ultimate story and be bolstered by your results.  My advice is to do both.  Writing the introduction is probably the most difficult part of writing the paper, which may come as a surprise to new students.  After all, the introduction is high-level and often doesn’t reflect the nitty gritty details of how difficult that experiment was to run, and how much toil went into writing the system.  To the contrary, distilling your work from those details so that the rest of the world can digest the takeaways—stepping out of the weeds and trying to figure out why your work matters—can take more effort than anything.  The same results can be presented in many different ways, so you will likely need to perform many iterations on your story.  Typically, you can “test” your story out on other colleagues and readers with a draft introduction in parallel with completing the rest of your work.</p>

<p>Write the introduction first—and last. I typically try (and encourage students) to write a draft of the paper’s introduction before writing other parts of the paper.  You will most likely eventually discard this draft completely, since it’s very hard to predict what one should be emphasizing in the introduction before the “meat” of the paper is done.  Yet, writing an early introduction draft allows a researcher to put the work in context, and to argue (1) what the problem is, (2) why it is hard, and (3) why the solution (if it is achieved) will be interesting to readers.  If an introduction draft can’t articulate answers to these questions, even at an early stage in the research, then the work likely needs some focus, as well.  When you write the second version of your introduction (after the rest of the paper is written), you are in a good position to refine your story, making sure that any claims you make are clearly supported by your results and data.  Your results should be stated as clearly and specifically as possible.  You should neither understate your results (which might cause the reader to lose interest and stop reading) or overstate them (which might cause the reader to be annoyed or “let down” when they dig in and find that you don’t deliver on what you’ve promised).</p>

<p>Perform some “landscaping” on your paper.  Your paper should be pleasing to the eye.  Care in preparation of the paper suggests that you also cared about the research itself.   Conversely, if the preparation of the paper is sloppy, how can the reader trust that you were not similarly sloppy in writing code, setting up and running your experiments, and analyzing your results?  Therefore, take some time to make your paper look nice. Here are a few quick tips on “landscaping” your paper.</p>

<p>Eliminate widows.  Section headings at the bottoms of columns or pages look sloppy.  Depending on your word-processing tool, there are good ways to get rid of widows.  In Latex, you can always use a “\vfill” to kick the section heading to the top of the next column.  Similarly, widows on paragraphs (paragraphs that end with a single word on the last line) look sloppy.  Typically you can eliminate such widows by wordsmithing (see below on omitting needless words).  Latex also has macros such as “\widowpenalty” that help ensure that the text layout avoids widows whenever possible.
Place (and create) signposts, figures, and graphs to create whitespace and avoid “walls of text”.  Reading long installments of technical writing is tiring, and seeing a page of uninterrupted technical writing can psychologically tire the reader before they even begin to read.  Create whitespace and take other steps to break up large chunks of text.  Use paragraph headings to break up long strings of text (ensuring that your headings match the topics you’ve outlined, of course).  Try to space figures, tables, and graphs throughout the paper so that most pages have a mix of figures and text.  If you don’t have a figure to break up the text, consider making one.  Often, a table summarizing results can be useful.  Or, you might find that a figure (or block of pseudocode) describes a concept better than a paragraph in your writeup.  Take steps to ensure that your writeup is not a long stream of text.
Check your spelling.  Run a spell checker.  Every word-processing tool has one, and a writeup that is rife with spelling errors reflects carelessness.  Again, if you can’t be bothered to check your spelling, why should a reader trust that you spent time debugging your experiment or code?  While a reader can forgive grammatical errors, especially when the writeup comes from a non-native English speaker, anyone can run a spell checker, so spelling errors simply reflect carelessness.  That said, not all spell-checkers are perfect, and sometimes typographical errors actually manifest as real words; spell checkers won’t catch those, so they should be used only as a first pass.
Make the last page look decent.  If you’ve edited your text down to remove redundancy, you may find that you have some extra space at the end of your paper.  Try to adjust your formatting so that the last page of the paper looks decent.  If your paper is double-column and you end with references, balance the references across the two columns so that both columns are both equally (partially) filled.  Latex has a “\balance” command that you can use to balance the columns on the last page of your writeup.  If you have a bit more time, you can also make small adjustments to margins, space between columns, space around figures, sizes of figures, and so forth to ensure that the last page doesn’t look like you just suddenly decided to stop writing.
Be Efficient
“I’m sorry I have had to write you such a long letter, but I did not have time to write you a short one.” –Blaise Pascal</p>

<p>After you’ve made a good impression, you still need to engage the reader at least long enough to convey your main message.  You should assume that the reader is busy, has a short attention span, and (unlike the situation when they are, say, reading a news article or novel) simply wants to learn what you’ve done as quickly as possible and then move on.  In contrast to writing a novel, your goal is not to hold the reader in suspense or to illustrate your command of vocabulary or literary construction.  Rather, the goal is to transfer information as efficiently as possible.</p>

<p>Tailor the length of your paper to the information content.  People sometimes feel compelled to stuff a paper to the conference’s or journal’s page limit (after all, if the paper is too short, isn’t there “more work to do”?).  I’ve had a few papers that do fall short of the page limit, although I’ve found that this scenario is the exception rather than the rule (see Blaise Pascal: it takes time to shorten a paper!).   Remember that your goal is to efficiently transfer information. Therefore, economize on words.  Do not add unnecessary sentences, paragraphs, or other content that do not support a topic or point that you’ve explicitly outlined.</p>

<p>Keep words simple and sentences short. The easier it is to read your paper, the more likely a reader will keep reading.  Therefore, don’t make the reader work harder than they have to.  On a sentence level, follow Strunk and White’s most indispensable advice: Omit needless words (e.g., “to” as opposed to “in order to”, “optimizing” instead of “the problem of optimizing”, “This module…” instead of “This is a module that”, “more quickly” instead of “in a shorter time”, “whether” instead of “the question as to whether”).   Avoid padding phrases such as “the fact that” and unnecessary adverbs (e.g., “eliminated” instead of “totally eliminated”, “fast” instead of “very fast”).  Keep words simple (e.g., “use” instead of “utilize”, “new” instead of “novel”), and keep sentences short.</p>

<p>Eliminate redundancy.  Always make at least one (and probably several) editing passes over your paper to cut out redundancy.  You likely (and hopefully) did not write your paper in a linear fashion, and different co-authors may have written different sections or pieces of the paper.  It’s likely that you’ve stated the same point multiple times throughout the paper.  Cutting redundancy takes practice, and it sometimes requires divorcing the editing process from your ego (after all, isn’t that sentence you wrote beautiful?  It’d be a shame to cut it, right?).  If you need help cutting, ask someone else (a co-author or colleague) to help you—they’re not as married to your text as you are.</p>

<p>Be as specific and precise as you can.  Precision is especially important when describing results, and when writing up an experiment or evaluation section.  For example, a good rule of thumb for writing up an evaluation section is:  Would someone be able to reproduce your experiment from your description?  If not, you need to be more clear.  In an evaluation section, clearly state your assumptions; in what context(s) do your results hold?  How general are they?  Clearly describe your evaluation setup, as it sets the context for the results themselves.  What machines did you use to run the evaluation?  What data did you gather to support your conclusions?  What algorithms did you use to analyze the data?  The evaluation setup should read like a recipe.  Someone reading it should be able to reproduce what you’ve done, at least well enough to understand the context of the results.  Similarly, the results should be clearly and precisely described.  Avoid writing sentences such as “This optimization significantly reduced the system’s running time.”  Such vague statements frustrate the reader.  Instead, substitute precise and specific information: “This optimization reduced the system’s running time by 20%”.</p>

<p>Use clear and consistent terminology.  Unclear, vague, and inconsistent terminology is incredibly frustrating and also typically reflects muddy thinking.  If you call something a “node” in one part of your paper, a “host” in another part of the paper, a “client” in another part, and a “machine” in yet another part, people will have absolutely no clue that all of these terms are in fact referring to the same thing.  Before you get too far along in the writing process, clearly define your lexicon.  Defining your terms up front can help clarify your own thinking, by helping you to identify and articulate the important concepts that you will present.  Ultimately, this clarity will be reflected in your writeup.</p>

<h3>Reduction to Practice: Write Every Day</h3>

<p>Writing a technical paper involves clearly presenting a good story, as efficiently as possible.  The above tips should help you compose your story and ensure that it “flows” and ultimately produce a final result that leaves a good impression and communicates your results as efficiently as possible.  But, simply reading this post won’t make you a good writer: putting these tips into practice takes tireless repetition.  Try writing something every day to practice these tips.  Keep a “running draft” of your research paper.  Start a blog and practice composing posts that present shorter and simpler ideas and thoughts than a full research paper.  Keep a diary or notebook.  Ultimately, becoming a good writer requires relentless, daily practice, with continual attention to the above tips.</p>

<p>original url:<a href="http://greatresearch.org/2013/10/11/storytelling-101-writing-tips-for-academics/">Storytelling 101: Writing Tips for Academics</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
